<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<aiml>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A chatbot is a software application used to conduct an on-line chat conversation via text or text-to-speech, in lieu of providing direct contact with a live human agent. Designed to convincingly simulate the way a human would behave as a conversational partner, chatbot systems typically require continuous tuning and testing, and many in production remain unable to adequately converse or pass the industry standard Turing test. The term "ChatterBot" was originally coined by Michael Mauldin (creator of the first Verbot) in 1994 to describe these conversational programs.</li>
<li>Chatbots are used in dialog systems for various purposes including customer service, request routing, or information gathering. While some chatbot applications use extensive word-classification processes, natural language processors, and sophisticated AI, others simply scan for general keywords and generate responses using common phrases obtained from an associated library or database.</li>
<li>Most chatbots are accessed on-line via website popups or through virtual assistants. They can be classified into usage categories that include: commerce (e-commerce via chat), education, entertainment, finance, health, news, and productivity.</li>
<li> artificial intelligence ... machines are made to behave in wondrous ways, often sufficient to dazzle even the most experienced observer. But once a particular program is unmasked, once its inner workings are explained ... its magic crumbles away; it stands revealed as a mere collection of procedures ... The observer says to himself "I could have written that". With that thought, he moves the program in question from the shelf marked "intelligent", to that reserved for curios ... The object of this paper is to cause just such a re-evaluation of the program about to be "explained". Few programs ever needed it more.ELIZA's key method of operation (copied by chatbot designers ever since) involves the recognition of clue words or phrases in the input, and the output of the corresponding pre-prepared or pre-programmed responses that can move the conversation forward in an apparently meaningful way (e.g. by responding to any input that contains the word 'MOTHER' with 'TELL ME MORE ABOUT YOUR FAMILY'). Thus an illusion of understanding is generated, even though the processing involved has been merely superficial. ELIZA showed that such an illusion is surprisingly easy to generate because human judges are so ready to give the benefit of the doubt when conversational responses are capable of being interpreted as "intelligent".</li>
<li>Interface designers have come to appreciate that humans' readiness to interpret computer output as genuinely conversational—even when it is actually based on rather simple pattern-matching—can be exploited for useful purposes. Most people prefer to engage with programs that are human-like, and this gives chatbot-style techniques a potentially useful role in interactive systems that need to elicit information from users, as long as that information is relatively straightforward and falls into predictable categories. Thus, for example, online help systems can usefully employ chatbot techniques to identify the area of help that users require, potentially providing a "friendlier" interface than a more formal search or menu system. This sort of usage holds the prospect of moving chatbot technology from Weizenbaum's "shelf ... reserved for curios" to that marked "genuinely useful computational methods".</li>
<li>Among the most notable early chatbots are ELIZA (1966) and PARRY (1972). More recent notable programs include A.L.I.C.E., Jabberwacky and D.U.D.E (Agence Nationale de la Recherche and CNRS 2006). While ELIZA and PARRY were used exclusively to simulate typed conversation, many chatbots now include other functional features, such as games and web searching abilities. In 1984, a book called The Policeman's Beard is Half Constructed was published, allegedly written by the chatbot Racter (though the program as released would not have been capable of doing so).</li>
<li>One pertinent field of AI research is natural language processing. Usually, weak AI fields employ specialized software or programming languages created specifically for the narrow function required. For example, A.L.I.C.E. uses a markup language called AIML, which is specific to its function as a conversational agent, and has since been adopted by various other developers of, so-called, Alicebots. Nevertheless, A.L.I.C.E. is still purely based on pattern matching techniques without any reasoning capabilities, the same technique ELIZA was using back in 1966. This is not strong AI, which would require sapience and logical reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>Jabberwacky learns new responses and context based on real-time user interactions, rather than being driven from a static database. Some more recent chatbots also combine real-time learning with evolutionary algorithms that optimize their ability to communicate based on each conversation held. Still, there is currently no general purpose conversational artificial intelligence, and some software developers focus on the practical aspect, information retrieval.</li>
<li>Chatbot competitions focus on the Turing test or more specific goals. Two such annual contests are the Loebner Prize and The Chatterbox Challenge (the latter has been offline since 2015, however, materials can still be found from web archives).</li>
<li>DBpedia created a chatbot during the GSoC of 2017. and can communicate through Facebook Messenger.</li>
<li>Many companies' chatbots run on messaging apps or simply via SMS. They are used for B2C customer service, sales and marketing.</li>
<li>In 2016, Facebook Messenger allowed developers to place chatbots on their platform. There were 30,000 bots created for Messenger in the first six months, rising to 100,000 by September 2017.</li>
<li>Since September 2017, this has also been as part of a pilot program on WhatsApp. Airlines KLM and Aeroméxico both announced their participation in the testing; both airlines had previously launched customer services on the Facebook Messenger platform.</li>
<li>The bots usually appear as one of the user's contacts, but can sometimes act as participants in a group chat.</li>
<li>Many banks, insurers, media companies, e-commerce companies, airlines, hotel chains, retailers, health care providers, government entities and restaurant chains have used chatbots to answer simple questions, increase customer engagement, for promotion, and to offer additional ways to order from them.</li>
<li>A 2017 study showed 4% of companies used chatbots. According to a 2016 study, 80% of businesses said they intended to have one by 2020.</li>
<li>Previous generations of chatbots were present on company websites, e.g. Ask Jenn from Alaska Airlines which debuted in 2008 or Expedia's virtual customer service agent which launched in 2011. The newer generation of chatbots includes IBM Watson-powered "Rocky", introduced in February 2017 by the New York City-based e-commerce company Rare Carat to provide information to prospective diamond buyers.</li>
<li>Used by marketers to script sequences of messages, very similar to an Autoresponder sequence. Such sequences can be triggered by user opt-in or the use of keywords within user interactions. After a trigger occurs a sequence of messages is delivered until the next anticipated user response. Each user response is used in the decision tree to help the chatbot navigate the response sequences to deliver the correct response message.</li>
<li>Other companies explore ways they can use chatbots internally, for example for Customer Support, Human Resources, or even in Internet-of-Things (IoT) projects. Overstock.com, for one, has reportedly launched a chatbot named Mila to automate certain simple yet time-consuming processes when requesting sick leave. Other large companies such as Lloyds Banking Group, Royal Bank of Scotland, Renault and Citroën are now using automated online assistants instead of call centres with humans to provide a first point of contact. A SaaS chatbot business ecosystem has been steadily growing since the F8 Conference when Facebook's Mark Zuckerberg unveiled that Messenger would allow chatbots into the app. In large companies, like in hospitals and aviation organizations, IT architects are designing reference architectures for Intelligent Chatbots that are used to unlock and share knowledge and experience in the organization more efficiently, and reduce the errors in answers from expert service desks significantly. These Intelligent Chatbots make use of all kinds of artificial intelligence like image moderation and natural language understanding (NLU), natural language generation (NLG), machine learning and deep learning.</li>
<li>Many high-tech banking organizations are looking to integrate automated AI-based solutions such as chatbots into their customer service in order to provide faster and cheaper assistance to their clients who are becoming increasingly comfortable with technology.  In particular, chatbots can efficiently conduct a dialogue, usually replacing other communication tools such as email, phone, or SMS. In banking, their major application is related to quick customer service answering common requests, as well as transactional support.</li>
<li>Several studies report significant reduction in the cost of customer services, expected to lead to billions of dollars of economic savings in the next ten years. In 2019, Gartner predicted that by 2021, 15% of all customer service interactions globally will be handled completely by AI.  A study by Juniper Research in 2019 estimates retail sales resulting from chatbot-based interactions will reach $112 billion by 2023.</li>
<li>Since 2016, when Facebook allowed businesses to deliver automated customer support, e-commerce guidance, content, and interactive experiences through chatbots, a large variety of chatbots were developed for the Facebook Messenger platform.</li>
<li>In 2016, Russia-based Tochka Bank launched the world's first Facebook bot for a range of financial services, including a possibility of making payments.</li>
<li>In July 2016, Barclays Africa also launched a Facebook chatbot, making it the first bank to do so in Africa.</li>
<li>The France's third-largest bank by total assets Société Générale launched their chatbot called SoBot in March 2018. While 80% of users of the SoBot expressed their satisfaction after having tested it, Société Générale deputy director Bertrand Cozzarolo stated that it will never replace the expertise provided by a human advisor.</li>
<li>The advantages of using chatbots for customer interactions in banking include cost reduction, financial advice, and 24/7 support.</li>
<li>Chatbots are also appearing in the healthcare industry. A study suggested that physicians in the United States believed that chatbots would be most beneficial for scheduling doctor appointments, locating health clinics, or providing medication information.</li>
<li>Whatsapp has tied up with the World Health Organisation (WHO) to make a chatbot service that answers users’ questions on Covid-19.</li>
<li>The Indian Government recently launched a chatbot called MyGov Corona Helpdesk, that works through Whatsapp and helps people access information about the Coronavirus (Covid-19) pandemic.</li>
<li>Certain patient groups are still reluctant to use chatbots. A mixed-methods study showed that people are still hesitant to use chatbots for their healthcare due to poor understanding of the technological complexity, the lack of empathy, and concerns about cyber-security. The analysis showed that while 6% had heard of a health chatbot and 3% had experience of using it, 67% perceived themselves as likely to use one within 12 months. The majority of participants would use a health chatbot for seeking general health information (78%), booking a medical appointment (78%), and looking for local health services (80%). However, a health chatbot was perceived as less suitable for seeking results of medical tests and seeking specialist advice such as sexual health. The analysis of attitudinal variables showed that most participants reported their preference for discussing their health with doctors (73%) and having access to reliable and accurate health information (93%). While 80% were curious about new technologies that could improve their health, 66% reported only seeking a doctor when experiencing a health problem and 65% thought that a chatbot was a good idea. Interestingly, 30% reported dislike about talking to computers, 41% felt it would be strange to discuss health matters with a chatbot and about half were unsure if they could trust the advice given by a chatbot. Therefore, perceived trustworthiness, individual attitudes towards bots, and dislike for talking to computers are the main barriers to health chatbots.</li>
<li>In New Zealand, the chatbot SAM – short for Semantic Analysis Machine (made by Nick Gerritsen of Touchtech) – has been developed. It is designed to share its political thoughts, for example on topics such as climate change, healthcare and education, etc. It talks to people through Facebook Messenger.</li>
<li>In India, the state government has launched a chatbot for its Aaple Sarkar platform, which provides conversational access to information regarding public services managed.</li>
<li>Chatbots have also been incorporated into devices not primarily meant for computing, such as toys.</li>
<li>Hello Barbie is an Internet-connected version of the doll that uses a chatbot provided by the company ToyTalk, which previously used the chatbot for a range of smartphone-based characters for children. These characters' behaviors are constrained by a set of rules that in effect emulate a particular character and produce a storyline.</li>
<li>The My Friend Cayla doll was marketed as a line of 18-inch (46 cm) dolls which uses speech recognition technology in conjunction with an Android or iOS mobile app to recognize the child's speech and have a conversation. It, like the Hello Barbie doll, attracted controversy due to vulnerabilities with the doll's Bluetooth stack and its use of data collected from the child's speech.</li>
<li>IBM's Watson computer has been used as the basis for chatbot-based educational toys for companies such as CogniToys intended to interact with children for educational purposes.</li>
<li>Malicious chatbots are frequently used to fill chat rooms with spam and advertisements, by mimicking human behavior and conversations or to entice people into revealing personal information, such as bank account numbers. They were commonly found on Yahoo! Messenger, Windows Live Messenger, AOL Instant Messenger and other instant messaging protocols. There has also been a published report of a chatbot used in a fake personal ad on a dating service's website.</li>
<li>Tay, an AI chatbot that learns from previous interaction, caused major controversy due to it being targeted by internet trolls on Twitter. The bot was exploited, and after 16 hours began to send extremely offensive Tweets to users. This suggests that although the bot learned effectively from experience, adequate protection was not put in place to prevent misuse.</li>
<li>If a text-sending algorithm can pass itself off as a human instead of a chatbot, its message would be more credible. Therefore, human-seeming chatbots with well-crafted online identities could start scattering fake news that seems plausible, for instance making false claims during a presidential election. With enough chatbots, it might be even possible to achieve artificial social proof.</li>
<li>The creation and implementation of chatbots is still a developing area, heavily related to artificial intelligence and machine learning, so the provided solutions, while possessing obvious advantages, have some important limitations in terms of functionalities and use cases. However, this is changing over time.</li>
<li>Chatbots are increasingly present in businesses and often are used to automate tasks that do not require skill-based talents. With customer service taking place via messaging apps as well as phone calls, there are growing numbers of use-cases where chatbot deployment gives organizations a clear return on investment. Call center workers may be particularly at risk from AI-driven chatbots.</li>
<li>A study by Forrester (June 2017) predicted that 25% of all jobs would be impacted by AI technologies by 2019.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MESSENGER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MESSENGER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MESSENGER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MESSENGER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ONE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Albert One is an AI chatterbot bot created by Robby Garner and designed to mimic the way humans make conversations using a multi-faceted approach in natural language programming.</li>
<li>In both 1998 and 1999, Albert One won the Loebner Prize Contest, a competition between chatterbots.</li>
<li>Some parts of Albert were deployed on the internet beginning in 1995, to gather information about what kinds of things people would say to a chatterbot. Another element of Albert One involved the building of a large database of human statements, and associated replies. This portion of the project was tested at the 1994-1997 Loebner Prize contests.</li>
<li>Albert was the first of Robby Garner's multifaceted bots. The Albert One system was composed of several subsystems. Among those were a version of Eliza, the therapist, Elivs, another Eliza-like bot, and several other helper applications working together in a hierarchical arrangement. As a continuation of the stimulus-response library, various other database queries and assertions were tested to arrive at each of Albert's responses. Robby went on to develop networked examples of this kind of hierarchical "glue" at The Turing Hub.</li>
<li>This computational linguistics-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ONE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CONTEST</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CONTEST *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CONTEST *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CONTEST</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALBERT ONE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALBERT ONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALBERT ONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALBERT ONE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ONE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A.L.I.C.E. (Artificial Linguistic Internet Computer Entity), also referred to as Alicebot, or simply Alice, is a natural language processing chatterbot—a program that engages in a conversation with a human by applying some heuristical pattern matching rules to the human's input. It was inspired by Joseph Weizenbaum's classical ELIZA program. It is one of the strongest programs of its type and has won the Loebner Prize, awarded to accomplished humanoid, talking robots, three times (in 2000, 2001, and 2004). The program is unable to pass the Turing test, as even the casual user will often expose its mechanistic aspects in short conversations.</li>
<li>Alice was originally composed by Richard Wallace; it "came to life" on November 23, 1995.  The program was rewritten in Java beginning in 1998.  The current incarnation of the Java implementation is Program D.  The program uses an XML Schema called AIML (Artificial Intelligence Markup Language) for specifying the heuristic conversation rules.</li>
<li>Alice code has been reported to be available as open source. The AIML source is available from ALICE A.I. Foundation on Google Code and from the GitHub account of Richard Wallace. These AIML files can be run using an AIML interpreter like Program O or Program AB.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JONZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JONZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JONZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JONZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROGRAM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROGRAM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RICHARD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RICHARD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RICHARD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RICHARD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ARTIFICIAL LINGUISTIC INTERNET COMPUTER ENTITY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ARTIFICIAL LINGUISTIC INTERNET COMPUTER ENTITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ARTIFICIAL LINGUISTIC INTERNET COMPUTER ENTITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ARTIFICIAL LINGUISTIC INTERNET COMPUTER ENTITY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIML</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A chatbot is a software application used to conduct an on-line chat conversation via text or text-to-speech, in lieu of providing direct contact with a live human agent. Designed to convincingly simulate the way a human would behave as a conversational partner, chatbot systems typically require continuous tuning and testing, and many in production remain unable to adequately converse or pass the industry standard Turing test. The term "ChatterBot" was originally coined by Michael Mauldin (creator of the first Verbot) in 1994 to describe these conversational programs.</li>
<li>Chatbots are used in dialog systems for various purposes including customer service, request routing, or information gathering. While some chatbot applications use extensive word-classification processes, natural language processors, and sophisticated AI, others simply scan for general keywords and generate responses using common phrases obtained from an associated library or database.</li>
<li>Most chatbots are accessed on-line via website popups or through virtual assistants. They can be classified into usage categories that include: commerce (e-commerce via chat), education, entertainment, finance, health, news, and productivity.</li>
<li> artificial intelligence ... machines are made to behave in wondrous ways, often sufficient to dazzle even the most experienced observer. But once a particular program is unmasked, once its inner workings are explained ... its magic crumbles away; it stands revealed as a mere collection of procedures ... The observer says to himself "I could have written that". With that thought, he moves the program in question from the shelf marked "intelligent", to that reserved for curios ... The object of this paper is to cause just such a re-evaluation of the program about to be "explained". Few programs ever needed it more.ELIZA's key method of operation (copied by chatbot designers ever since) involves the recognition of clue words or phrases in the input, and the output of the corresponding pre-prepared or pre-programmed responses that can move the conversation forward in an apparently meaningful way (e.g. by responding to any input that contains the word 'MOTHER' with 'TELL ME MORE ABOUT YOUR FAMILY'). Thus an illusion of understanding is generated, even though the processing involved has been merely superficial. ELIZA showed that such an illusion is surprisingly easy to generate because human judges are so ready to give the benefit of the doubt when conversational responses are capable of being interpreted as "intelligent".</li>
<li>Interface designers have come to appreciate that humans' readiness to interpret computer output as genuinely conversational—even when it is actually based on rather simple pattern-matching—can be exploited for useful purposes. Most people prefer to engage with programs that are human-like, and this gives chatbot-style techniques a potentially useful role in interactive systems that need to elicit information from users, as long as that information is relatively straightforward and falls into predictable categories. Thus, for example, online help systems can usefully employ chatbot techniques to identify the area of help that users require, potentially providing a "friendlier" interface than a more formal search or menu system. This sort of usage holds the prospect of moving chatbot technology from Weizenbaum's "shelf ... reserved for curios" to that marked "genuinely useful computational methods".</li>
<li>Among the most notable early chatbots are ELIZA (1966) and PARRY (1972). More recent notable programs include A.L.I.C.E., Jabberwacky and D.U.D.E (Agence Nationale de la Recherche and CNRS 2006). While ELIZA and PARRY were used exclusively to simulate typed conversation, many chatbots now include other functional features, such as games and web searching abilities. In 1984, a book called The Policeman's Beard is Half Constructed was published, allegedly written by the chatbot Racter (though the program as released would not have been capable of doing so).</li>
<li>One pertinent field of AI research is natural language processing. Usually, weak AI fields employ specialized software or programming languages created specifically for the narrow function required. For example, A.L.I.C.E. uses a markup language called AIML, which is specific to its function as a conversational agent, and has since been adopted by various other developers of, so-called, Alicebots. Nevertheless, A.L.I.C.E. is still purely based on pattern matching techniques without any reasoning capabilities, the same technique ELIZA was using back in 1966. This is not strong AI, which would require sapience and logical reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>Jabberwacky learns new responses and context based on real-time user interactions, rather than being driven from a static database. Some more recent chatbots also combine real-time learning with evolutionary algorithms that optimize their ability to communicate based on each conversation held. Still, there is currently no general purpose conversational artificial intelligence, and some software developers focus on the practical aspect, information retrieval.</li>
<li>Chatbot competitions focus on the Turing test or more specific goals. Two such annual contests are the Loebner Prize and The Chatterbox Challenge (the latter has been offline since 2015, however, materials can still be found from web archives).</li>
<li>DBpedia created a chatbot during the GSoC of 2017. and can communicate through Facebook Messenger.</li>
<li>Many companies' chatbots run on messaging apps or simply via SMS. They are used for B2C customer service, sales and marketing.</li>
<li>In 2016, Facebook Messenger allowed developers to place chatbots on their platform. There were 30,000 bots created for Messenger in the first six months, rising to 100,000 by September 2017.</li>
<li>Since September 2017, this has also been as part of a pilot program on WhatsApp. Airlines KLM and Aeroméxico both announced their participation in the testing; both airlines had previously launched customer services on the Facebook Messenger platform.</li>
<li>The bots usually appear as one of the user's contacts, but can sometimes act as participants in a group chat.</li>
<li>Many banks, insurers, media companies, e-commerce companies, airlines, hotel chains, retailers, health care providers, government entities and restaurant chains have used chatbots to answer simple questions, increase customer engagement, for promotion, and to offer additional ways to order from them.</li>
<li>A 2017 study showed 4% of companies used chatbots. According to a 2016 study, 80% of businesses said they intended to have one by 2020.</li>
<li>Previous generations of chatbots were present on company websites, e.g. Ask Jenn from Alaska Airlines which debuted in 2008 or Expedia's virtual customer service agent which launched in 2011. The newer generation of chatbots includes IBM Watson-powered "Rocky", introduced in February 2017 by the New York City-based e-commerce company Rare Carat to provide information to prospective diamond buyers.</li>
<li>Used by marketers to script sequences of messages, very similar to an Autoresponder sequence. Such sequences can be triggered by user opt-in or the use of keywords within user interactions. After a trigger occurs a sequence of messages is delivered until the next anticipated user response. Each user response is used in the decision tree to help the chatbot navigate the response sequences to deliver the correct response message.</li>
<li>Other companies explore ways they can use chatbots internally, for example for Customer Support, Human Resources, or even in Internet-of-Things (IoT) projects. Overstock.com, for one, has reportedly launched a chatbot named Mila to automate certain simple yet time-consuming processes when requesting sick leave. Other large companies such as Lloyds Banking Group, Royal Bank of Scotland, Renault and Citroën are now using automated online assistants instead of call centres with humans to provide a first point of contact. A SaaS chatbot business ecosystem has been steadily growing since the F8 Conference when Facebook's Mark Zuckerberg unveiled that Messenger would allow chatbots into the app. In large companies, like in hospitals and aviation organizations, IT architects are designing reference architectures for Intelligent Chatbots that are used to unlock and share knowledge and experience in the organization more efficiently, and reduce the errors in answers from expert service desks significantly. These Intelligent Chatbots make use of all kinds of artificial intelligence like image moderation and natural language understanding (NLU), natural language generation (NLG), machine learning and deep learning.</li>
<li>Many high-tech banking organizations are looking to integrate automated AI-based solutions such as chatbots into their customer service in order to provide faster and cheaper assistance to their clients who are becoming increasingly comfortable with technology.  In particular, chatbots can efficiently conduct a dialogue, usually replacing other communication tools such as email, phone, or SMS. In banking, their major application is related to quick customer service answering common requests, as well as transactional support.</li>
<li>Several studies report significant reduction in the cost of customer services, expected to lead to billions of dollars of economic savings in the next ten years. In 2019, Gartner predicted that by 2021, 15% of all customer service interactions globally will be handled completely by AI.  A study by Juniper Research in 2019 estimates retail sales resulting from chatbot-based interactions will reach $112 billion by 2023.</li>
<li>Since 2016, when Facebook allowed businesses to deliver automated customer support, e-commerce guidance, content, and interactive experiences through chatbots, a large variety of chatbots were developed for the Facebook Messenger platform.</li>
<li>In 2016, Russia-based Tochka Bank launched the world's first Facebook bot for a range of financial services, including a possibility of making payments.</li>
<li>In July 2016, Barclays Africa also launched a Facebook chatbot, making it the first bank to do so in Africa.</li>
<li>The France's third-largest bank by total assets Société Générale launched their chatbot called SoBot in March 2018. While 80% of users of the SoBot expressed their satisfaction after having tested it, Société Générale deputy director Bertrand Cozzarolo stated that it will never replace the expertise provided by a human advisor.</li>
<li>The advantages of using chatbots for customer interactions in banking include cost reduction, financial advice, and 24/7 support.</li>
<li>Chatbots are also appearing in the healthcare industry. A study suggested that physicians in the United States believed that chatbots would be most beneficial for scheduling doctor appointments, locating health clinics, or providing medication information.</li>
<li>Whatsapp has tied up with the World Health Organisation (WHO) to make a chatbot service that answers users’ questions on Covid-19.</li>
<li>The Indian Government recently launched a chatbot called MyGov Corona Helpdesk, that works through Whatsapp and helps people access information about the Coronavirus (Covid-19) pandemic.</li>
<li>Certain patient groups are still reluctant to use chatbots. A mixed-methods study showed that people are still hesitant to use chatbots for their healthcare due to poor understanding of the technological complexity, the lack of empathy, and concerns about cyber-security. The analysis showed that while 6% had heard of a health chatbot and 3% had experience of using it, 67% perceived themselves as likely to use one within 12 months. The majority of participants would use a health chatbot for seeking general health information (78%), booking a medical appointment (78%), and looking for local health services (80%). However, a health chatbot was perceived as less suitable for seeking results of medical tests and seeking specialist advice such as sexual health. The analysis of attitudinal variables showed that most participants reported their preference for discussing their health with doctors (73%) and having access to reliable and accurate health information (93%). While 80% were curious about new technologies that could improve their health, 66% reported only seeking a doctor when experiencing a health problem and 65% thought that a chatbot was a good idea. Interestingly, 30% reported dislike about talking to computers, 41% felt it would be strange to discuss health matters with a chatbot and about half were unsure if they could trust the advice given by a chatbot. Therefore, perceived trustworthiness, individual attitudes towards bots, and dislike for talking to computers are the main barriers to health chatbots.</li>
<li>In New Zealand, the chatbot SAM – short for Semantic Analysis Machine (made by Nick Gerritsen of Touchtech) – has been developed. It is designed to share its political thoughts, for example on topics such as climate change, healthcare and education, etc. It talks to people through Facebook Messenger.</li>
<li>In India, the state government has launched a chatbot for its Aaple Sarkar platform, which provides conversational access to information regarding public services managed.</li>
<li>Chatbots have also been incorporated into devices not primarily meant for computing, such as toys.</li>
<li>Hello Barbie is an Internet-connected version of the doll that uses a chatbot provided by the company ToyTalk, which previously used the chatbot for a range of smartphone-based characters for children. These characters' behaviors are constrained by a set of rules that in effect emulate a particular character and produce a storyline.</li>
<li>The My Friend Cayla doll was marketed as a line of 18-inch (46 cm) dolls which uses speech recognition technology in conjunction with an Android or iOS mobile app to recognize the child's speech and have a conversation. It, like the Hello Barbie doll, attracted controversy due to vulnerabilities with the doll's Bluetooth stack and its use of data collected from the child's speech.</li>
<li>IBM's Watson computer has been used as the basis for chatbot-based educational toys for companies such as CogniToys intended to interact with children for educational purposes.</li>
<li>Malicious chatbots are frequently used to fill chat rooms with spam and advertisements, by mimicking human behavior and conversations or to entice people into revealing personal information, such as bank account numbers. They were commonly found on Yahoo! Messenger, Windows Live Messenger, AOL Instant Messenger and other instant messaging protocols. There has also been a published report of a chatbot used in a fake personal ad on a dating service's website.</li>
<li>Tay, an AI chatbot that learns from previous interaction, caused major controversy due to it being targeted by internet trolls on Twitter. The bot was exploited, and after 16 hours began to send extremely offensive Tweets to users. This suggests that although the bot learned effectively from experience, adequate protection was not put in place to prevent misuse.</li>
<li>If a text-sending algorithm can pass itself off as a human instead of a chatbot, its message would be more credible. Therefore, human-seeming chatbots with well-crafted online identities could start scattering fake news that seems plausible, for instance making false claims during a presidential election. With enough chatbots, it might be even possible to achieve artificial social proof.</li>
<li>The creation and implementation of chatbots is still a developing area, heavily related to artificial intelligence and machine learning, so the provided solutions, while possessing obvious advantages, have some important limitations in terms of functionalities and use cases. However, this is changing over time.</li>
<li>Chatbots are increasingly present in businesses and often are used to automate tasks that do not require skill-based talents. With customer service taking place via messaging apps as well as phone calls, there are growing numbers of use-cases where chatbot deployment gives organizations a clear return on investment. Call center workers may be particularly at risk from AI-driven chatbots.</li>
<li>A study by Forrester (June 2017) predicted that 25% of all jobs would be impacted by AI technologies by 2019.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MESSENGER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MESSENGER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MESSENGER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MESSENGER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FACEBOOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNLIKE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Cleverbot is a chatterbot web application that uses an artificial intelligence (AI) algorithm to have conversations with humans. It was created by British AI scientist Rollo Carpenter. It was preceded by Jabberwacky, a chatbot project that began in 1986 and went online in 1997. In its first decade, Cleverbot held several thousand conversations with Carpenter and his associates. Since launching on the web, the number of conversations held has exceeded 150 million. Besides the web application, Cleverbot is also available as an iOS, Android, and Windows Phone app.</li>
<li>Unlike some other chatterbots, Cleverbot's responses are not pre-programmed. Instead, it learns from human input: Humans type into the box below the Cleverbot logo and the system finds all keywords or an exact phrase matching the input. After searching through its saved conversations, it responds to the input by finding how a human responded to that input when it was asked, in part or in full, by Cleverbot.</li>
<li>Cleverbot participated in a formal Turing test at the 2011 Techniche festival at the Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati on 3 September 2011. Out of the 1334 votes cast, Cleverbot was judged to be 59.3% human, compared to the rating of 63.3% human achieved by human participants. A score of 50.05% or higher is often considered to be a passing grade. The software running for the event had to handle just 1 or 2 simultaneous requests, whereas online Cleverbot is usually talking to around 10,000 to 50,000 people at once.</li>
<li>Cleverbot is constantly growing in data size at a rate of 400 to 7 million interactions per second. Updates to the software have been mostly behind the scenes. In 2014, Cleverbot was upgraded to use GPU serving techniques. Unlike Eliza, the program does not respond in a fixed way, instead choosing its responses heuristically using fuzzy logic, the whole of the conversation being compared to the millions that have taken place before. Cleverbot now uses over 279 million interactions, about 3-4% of the data it has already accumulated. The developers of Cleverbot are attempting to build a new version using machine learning techniques.</li>
<li>A significant part of the engine behind Cleverbot and an API for accessing it has been made available to developers in the form of Cleverscript. A service for directly accessing Cleverbot has been made available to developers in the form of Cleverbot.io.</li>
<li>An app that uses the Cleverscript engine to play a game of 20 Questions, has been launched under the name Clevernator. Unlike other such games, the player asks the questions and it is the role of the AI to understand, and answer factually. An app that allows owners to create and talk to their own small Cleverbot-like AI has been launched, called Cleverme! for Apple products.</li>
<li>In early 2017, a Twitch stream of two Google Home devices modified to talk to each other using Cleverbot.io garnered over 700,000 visitors and over 30,000 peak concurrent viewers.</li>
<li>In late 2010, Cleverbot received widespread media attention after being featured in the popular creepypasta ARG web serial Ben Drowned by Alexander D. Hall.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNLIKE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNLIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNLIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CLEVERBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CLEVERBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CLEVERBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CLEVERBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TECHNIQUES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TECHNIQUES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TECHNIQUES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TECHNIQUES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JABBERWACKY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JABBERWACKY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JABBERWACKY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JABBERWACKY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNLIKE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SBAITSO</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Dr. Sbaitso /ˈsbeɪtsoʊ/ SBAY-tsoh /səˈb-/ /ˈzb-/ is an artificial intelligence speech synthesis program released late in 1991  by Creative Labs in Singapore for MS DOS-based personal computers.</li>
<li>Dr. Sbaitso was distributed with various sound cards manufactured by Creative Labs (the name was an acronym for Sound Blaster Acting Intelligent Text to Speech Operator) in the early 1990s.</li>
<li>The program "conversed" with the user as if it were a psychologist, though most of its responses were along the lines of "WHY DO YOU FEEL THAT WAY?" rather than any sort of complicated interaction.  When confronted with a phrase it could not understand, it would often reply with something such as "THAT'S NOT MY PROBLEM".  Dr. Sbaitso repeated text out loud that was typed after the word "SAY". Repeated swearing or abusive behavior on the part of the user caused Dr. Sbaitso to "break down" in a "PARITY ERROR" before resetting itself.</li>
<li>The program was designed to showcase the digitized voices the cards were able to produce, though the quality was far from lifelike. Additionally, there was a version of this program for Microsoft Windows through the use of a program called Prody Parrot; this version of the software featured a more detailed graphical user interface.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SBAITSO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SBAITSO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SBAITSO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CREATIVE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CREATIVE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CREATIVE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CREATIVE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LABS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LABS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LABS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LABS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROGRAM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROGRAM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DR. SBAITSO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DR. SBAITSO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DR. SBAITSO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DR. SBAITSO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SBAITSO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>and used rules, dictated in the script, to respond with non-directional questions to user inputs. As such, ELIZA was one of the first chatterbots and one of the first programs capable of attempting the Turing test.</li>
<li>ELIZA's creator, Weizenbaum, regarded the program as a method to show the superficiality of communication between man and machine, but was surprised by the number of individuals who attributed human-like feelings to the computer program, including Weizenbaum’s secretary. Many academics believed that the program would be able to positively influence the lives of many people, particularly those suffering from psychological issues, and that it could aid doctors working on such patients' treatment. While ELIZA was capable of engaging in discourse, ELIZA could not converse with true understanding. However, many early users were convinced of ELIZA’s intelligence and understanding, despite Weizenbaum’s insistence to the contrary.</li>
<li>Joseph Weizenbaum’s ELIZA, running the DOCTOR script, was created to provide a parody of "the responses of a non-directional psychotherapist in an initial psychiatric interview" and to "demonstrate that the communication between man and machine was superficial". While ELIZA is best known for acting in the manner of a psychotherapist, the speech patterns are due to the data and instructions supplied by the DOCTOR script. ELIZA itself examined the text for keywords, applied values to said keywords, and transformed the input into an output; the script that ELIZA ran determined the keywords, set the values of keywords, and set the rules of transformation for the output. Weizenbaum chose to make the DOCTOR script in the context of psychotherapy to "sidestep the problem of giving the program a data base of real-world knowledge", as in a Rogerian therapeutic situation, the program had only to reflect back the patient's statements. The algorithms of DOCTOR allowed for a deceptively intelligent response, which deceived many individuals when first using the program.</li>
<li>Weizenbaum named his program ELIZA after Eliza Doolittle, a working-class character in George Bernard Shaw's Pygmalion. According to Weizenbaum, ELIZA's ability to be "incrementally improved" by various users made it similar to Eliza Doolittle, since Eliza Doolittle was taught to speak with an upper-class accent in Shaw's play. However, unlike in Shaw's play, ELIZA is incapable of learning new patterns of speech or new words through interaction alone. Edits must be made directly to ELIZA’s active script in order to change the manner by which the program operates.</li>
<li>In 1966, interactive computing (via a teletype) was new. It was 15 years before the personal computer became familiar to the general public, and three decades before most people encountered attempts at natural language processing in Internet services like Ask.com or PC help systems such as Microsoft Office Clippit. Although those programs included years of research and work, ELIZA remains a milestone simply because it was the first time a programmer had attempted such a human-machine interaction with the goal of creating the illusion (however brief) of human–human interaction.</li>
<li>At the ICCC 1972 ELIZA was brought together with another early artificial-intelligence program named PARRY for a computer-only conversation. While ELIZA was built to speak as a doctor, PARRY was intended to simulate a patient with schizophrenia.</li>
<li>Weizenbaum originally wrote ELIZA in MAD-Slip for the IBM 7094, as a program to make natural-language conversation possible with a computer. To accomplish this, Weizenbaum identified five "fundamental technical problems" for ELIZA to overcome: the identification of critical words, the discovery of a minimal context, the choice of appropriate transformations, the generation of responses appropriate to the transformation or in the absence of critical words and the provision of an ending capacity for ELIZA scripts. Weizenbaum solved these problems in his ELIZA program and made ELIZA such that it had no built-in contextual framework or universe of discourse. However, this required ELIZA to have a script of instructions on how to respond to inputs from users.</li>
<li>ELIZA starts its process of responding to an input by a user by first examining the text input for a "keyword". A "keyword" is a word designated as important by the acting ELIZA script, which assigns to each keyword a precedence number, or a RANK, designed by the programmer. If such words are found, they are put into a "keystack", with the keyword of the highest RANK at the top. The input sentence is then manipulated and transformed as the rule associated with the keyword of the highest RANK directs. For example, when the DOCTOR script encounters words such as "alike" or "same", it would output a message pertaining to similarity, in this case “In what way?”, as these words had high precedence number. This also demonstrates how certain words, as dictated by the script, can be manipulated regardless of contextual considerations, such as switching first-person pronouns and second-person pronouns and vice versa, as these too had high precedence numbers. Such words with high precedence numbers are deemed superior to conversational patterns and are treated independently of contextual patterns.</li>
<li>Following the first examination, the next step of the process is to apply an appropriate transformation rule, which includes two parts: the "decomposition rule" and the "reassembly rule". First, the input is reviewed for syntactical patterns in order to establish the minimal context necessary to respond. Using the keywords and other nearby words from the input, different disassembly rules are tested until an appropriate pattern is found. Using the script's rules, the sentence is then "dismantled" and arranged into sections of the component parts as the "decomposition rule for the highest-ranking keyword" dictates. The example that Weizenbaum gives is the input "I are very helpful" (remembering that "I" is "You" transformed), which is broken into (1) empty (2) "I" (3) "are" (4) "very helpful". The decomposition rule has broken the phrase into four small segments that contain both the keywords and the information in the sentence.</li>
<li>The decomposition rule then designates a particular reassembly rule, or set of reassembly rules, to follow when reconstructing the sentence. The reassembly rule takes the fragments of the input that the decomposition rule had created, rearranges them, and adds in programmed words to create a response. Using Weizenbaum's example previously stated, such a reassembly rule would take the fragments and apply them to the phrase "What makes you think I am (4)", which would result in "What makes you think I am very helpful?". This example is rather simple, since depending upon the disassembly rule, the output could be significantly more complex and use more of the input from the user. However, from this reassembly, ELIZA then sends the constructed sentence to the user in the form of text on the screen.</li>
<li>These steps represent the bulk of the procedures that ELIZA follows in order to create a response from a typical input, though there are several specialized situations that ELIZA/DOCTOR can respond to. One Weizenbaum specifically wrote about was when there is no keyword. One solution was to have ELIZA respond with a remark that lacked content, such as "I see" or "Please go on". The second method was to use a "MEMORY" structure, which recorded prior recent inputs, and would use these inputs to create a response referencing a part of the earlier conversation when encountered with no keywords. This was possible due to Slip’s ability to tag words for other usage, which simultaneously allowed ELIZA to examine, store and repurpose words for usage in outputs.</li>
<li>While these functions were all framed in ELIZA's programming, the exact manner by which the program dismantled, examined, and reassembled inputs is determined by the operating script. The script is not static and can be edited, or a new one created, as is necessary for the operation in the context needed. This would allow the program to be applied in multiple situations, including the well-known DOCTOR script, which simulates a Rogerian psychotherapist.</li>
<li>Weizenbaum's original MAD-SLIP implementation was re-written in Lisp by Bernie Cosell. A BASIC version appeared in Creative Computing in 1977 (although it was written in 1973 by Jeff Shrager). This version, which was ported to many of the earliest personal computers, appears to have been subsequently translated into many other versions in many other languages.</li>
<li>Another version of Eliza popular among software engineers is the version that comes with the default release of GNU Emacs, and which can be accessed by typing M-x doctor from most modern Emacs implementations.</li>
<li>In 1969, George Lucas and Walter Murch incorporated an Eliza-like dialogue interface in their screenplay for the feature film THX-1138. Inhabitants of the underground future world of THX, when stressed, would retreat to "confession booths" and initiate a one-sided Eliza-formula conversation with a Jesus-faced computer who claimed to be "Omm".</li>
<li>ELIZA influenced a number of early computer games by demonstrating additional kinds of interface designs. Don Daglow wrote an enhanced version of the program called Ecala on a DEC PDP-10 minicomputer at Pomona College in 1973 before writing the computer role-playing game Dungeon (1975).</li>
<li>ELIZA is given credit as additional vocals on track 10 of the eponymous Information Society album.</li>
<li>In the 2008 anime RD Sennou Chousashitsu, aka Real Drive, a character named Eliza Weizenbaum appears, an obvious tribute to ELIZA and Joseph Weizenbaum. Her behavior in the story often mimics the responses of the ELIZA program.</li>
<li>The 2011 video game Deus Ex: Human Revolution features an artificial-intelligence Picus TV Network newsreader named Eliza Cassan.</li>
<li>In January 2018, the twelfth episode of the American sitcom Young Sheldon starred the protagonist "conversing" with ELIZA, hoping to resolve a domestic issue.</li>
<li>On July 19, 2018, ELIZA was in a brief mention by the protagonist of the movie Zoe to support his reasoning behind why his relationship with Zoe, a hyper-realistic AI, wasn't real.</li>
<li>On August 12, 2019, independent game developer Zachtronics published a visual novel called Eliza, about an AI-based counseling service inspired by ELIZA.</li>
<li>Lay responses to ELIZA were disturbing to Weizenbaum and motivated him to write his book Computer Power and Human Reason: From Judgment to Calculation, in which he explains the limits of computers, as he wants to make clear his opinion that the anthropomorphic views of computers are just a reduction of the human being and any life form for that matter. In the independent documentary film Plug and Pray (2010) Weizenbaum said that only people who misunderstood ELIZA called it a sensation.</li>
<li>The Israeli poet David Avidan, who was fascinated with future technologies and their relation to art, desired to explore the use of computers for writing literature. He conducted several conversations with an APL implementation of ELIZA and published them – in English, and in his own translation to Hebrew – under the title My Electronic Psychiatrist – Eight Authentic Talks with a Computer. In the foreword he presented it as a form of constrained writing.</li>
<li>There are many programs based on ELIZA in different programming languages. In 1980 a company called "Don't Ask Software" created a version called "Abuse" for the Apple II, Atari, and Commodore 64 computers, which verbally abused the user based on the user's input. Other versions adapted ELIZA around a religious theme, such as ones featuring Jesus (both serious and comedic), and another Apple II variant called I Am Buddha. The 1980 game The Prisoner incorporated ELIZA-style interaction within its gameplay. In 1988 the British artist and friend of Weizenbaum Brian Reffin Smith created two art-oriented ELIZA-style programs written in BASIC, one called "Critic" and the other "Artist", running on two separate Amiga 1000 computers and showed them at the exhibition "Salamandre" in the Musée du Berry, Bourges, France. The visitor was supposed to help them converse by typing in to "Artist" what "Critic" said, and vice versa. The secret was that the two programs were identical. GNU Emacs formerly had a psychoanalyze-pinhead command that simulates a session between ELIZA and Zippy the Pinhead. The Zippyisms were removed due to copyright issues, but the DOCTOR program remains.</li>
<li>ELIZA has been referenced in popular culture and continues to be a source of inspiration for programmers and developers focused on artificial intelligence. It was also featured in a 2012 exhibit at Harvard University titled "Go Ask A.L.I.C.E", as part of a celebration of mathematician Alan Turing's 100th birthday. The exhibit explores Turing's lifelong fascination with the interaction between humans and computers, pointing to ELIZA as one of the earliest realizations of Turing's ideas.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WEIZENBAUM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WEIZENBAUM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WEIZENBAUM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WEIZENBAUM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DOCTOR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DOCTOR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DOCTOR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DOCTOR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RANK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RANK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RANK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RANK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TURING</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Eugene Goostman is a chatbot that some regard as having passed the Turing test, a test of a computer's ability to communicate indistinguishably from a human. Developed in Saint Petersburg in 2001 by a group of three programmers, the Russian-born Vladimir Veselov, Ukrainian-born Eugene Demchenko, and Russian-born Sergey Ulasen, Goostman is portrayed as a 13-year-old Ukrainian boy—characteristics that are intended to induce forgiveness in those with whom it interacts for its grammatical errors and lack of general knowledge.</li>
<li>The Goostman bot has competed in a number of Turing test contests since its creation, and finished second in the 2005 and 2008 Loebner Prize contest. In June 2012, at an event marking what would have been the 100th birthday of the test's author, Alan Turing, Goostman won a competition promoted as the largest-ever Turing test contest, in which it successfully convinced 29% of its judges that it was human.</li>
<li>On 7 June 2014, at a contest marking the 60th anniversary of Turing's death, 33% of the event's judges thought that Goostman was human; the event's organiser Kevin Warwick considered it to have passed Turing's test as a result, per Turing's prediction in his 1950 paper Computing Machinery and Intelligence, that by the year 2000, machines would be capable of fooling 30% of human judges after five minutes of questioning. The validity and relevance of the announcement of Goostman's pass was questioned by critics, who noted the exaggeration of the achievement by Warwick, the bot's use of personality quirks and humour in an attempt to misdirect users from its non-human tendencies and lack of real intelligence, along with "passes" achieved by other chatbots at similar events.</li>
<li>Eugene Goostman is portrayed as being a 13-year-old boy from Odessa, Ukraine, who has a pet guinea pig and a father who is a gynaecologist. Veselov stated that Goostman was designed to be a "character with a believable personality". The choice of age was intentional, as, in Veselov's opinion, a thirteen-year-old is "not too old to know everything and not too young to know nothing". Goostman's young age also induces people who "converse" with him to forgive minor grammatical errors in his responses. In 2014, work was made on improving the bot's "dialog controller", allowing Goostman to output more human-like dialogue.</li>
<li>Scott: Which is bigger, a shoebox or Mount Everest?</li>
<li>Scott: How many legs does a camel have?</li>
<li>Eugene: Something between 2 and 4. Maybe, three? :-))) By the way, I still don’t know your specialty – or, possibly, I’ve missed it?</li>
<li>Scott: How many legs does a millipede have?</li>
<li>Eugene: Just two, but Chernobyl mutants may have up two five. I know you are supposed to trick me.</li>
<li>Scott: No, I need to know that you're not a chatbot. Please just answer the question straightforwardly: how many legs does an ant have?</li>
<li>Eugene Goostman has competed in a number of Turing test competitions, including the Loebner Prize contest; it finished joint second in the Loebner test in 2001, and came second to Jabberwacky in 2005 and to Elbot in 2008. On 23 June 2012, Goostman won a Turing test competition at Bletchley Park in Milton Keynes, held to mark the centenary of its namesake, Alan Turing. The competition, which featured five bots, twenty-five hidden humans, and thirty judges, was considered to be the largest-ever Turing test contest by its organizers. After a series of five-minute-long text conversations, 29% of the judges were convinced that the bot was an actual human.</li>
<li>Some will claim that the Test has already been passed. The words Turing Test have been applied to similar competitions around the world. However this event involved more simultaneous comparison tests than ever before, was independently verified and, crucially, the conversations were unrestricted. A true Turing Test does not set the questions or topics prior to the conversations.In his 1950 paper "Computing Machinery and Intelligence", Turing predicted that by the year 2000, computer programs would be sufficiently advanced that the average interrogator would, after five minutes of questioning, "not have more than 70 per cent chance" of correctly guessing whether they were speaking to a human or a machine. Although Turing phrased this as a prediction rather than a "threshold for intelligence", commentators believe that Warwick had chosen to interpret it as meaning that if 30% of interrogators were fooled, the software had "passed the Turing test".</li>
<li>Warwick's claim that Eugene Goostman was the first ever chatbot to pass a Turing test was met with scepticism; critics acknowledged similar "passes" made in the past by other chatbots under the 30% criteria, including PC Therapist in 1991 (which tricked 5 of 10 judges, 50%), and at the Techniche festival in 2011, where a modified version of Cleverbot tricked 59.3% of 1334 votes (which included the 30 judges, along with an audience). Cleverbot's developer, Rollo Carpenter, argued that Turing tests can only prove that a machine can "imitate" intelligence rather than show actual intelligence.</li>
<li>Gary Marcus was critical of Warwick's claims, arguing that Goostman's "success" was only the result of a "cleverly-coded piece of software", going on to say that "it's easy to see how an untrained judge might mistake wit for reality, but once you have an understanding of how this sort of system works, the constant misdirection and deflection becomes obvious, even irritating. The illusion, in other words, is fleeting." While acknowledging IBM's Deep Blue and Watson projects—single-purpose computer systems meant for playing chess and the quiz show Jeopardy! respectively—as examples of computer systems that show a degree of intelligence in their specialised field, he further argued that they were not an equivalent to a computer system that shows "broad" intelligence, and could—for example, watch a television programme and answer questions on its content. Marcus stated that "no existing combination of hardware and software can learn completely new things at will the way a clever child can." However, he still believed that there were potential uses for technology such as that of Goostman, specifically suggesting the creation of "believable", interactive video game characters.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TURING</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TURING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TURING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOSTMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOSTMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOSTMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOSTMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EUGENE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EUGENE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EUGENE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EUGENE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JUDGES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JUDGES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JUDGES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JUDGES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SCOTT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SCOTT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SCOTT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SCOTT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EUGENE GOOSTMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EUGENE GOOSTMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EUGENE GOOSTMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EUGENE GOOSTMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TURING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FLOK</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>flok (formerly Loyalblocks) was an American tech startup based in New York City that provides marketing services such as chatbots/AI, customer loyalty programs, mobile apps and CRM services to local businesses.</li>
<li>In January 2017, the company was acquired by Wix.com.</li>
<li>Around March 2017, flok ceased communication.</li>
<li>On October 1, 2019, flok communicated via email stating that Flok is shutting down on March 1st, 2020.</li>
<li>On March 1, 2020, flok communicated via email stating that Flok has officially shut down.</li>
<li>flok was founded in 2011 by Ido Gaver and Eran Kirshenboim and has offices in Tel Aviv, Israel. In May 2013, flok secured a $9 million Series A Round from General Catalyst Partners with participation from Founder Collective and existing investor Gemini Israel Ventures. In total, flok has raised over $18 million in venture capital in three rounds.</li>
<li>In May 2014, flok announced a self-service loyalty platform for SMBs to build their own programs with beacon integration. At that time, approximately 40,000 businesses were using the service. In 2016, flok released a turnkey chatbot service for local businesses, and was featured in AdWeek for developing the first "weed bot" chatbot for a California cannabis business.</li>
<li>flok offers an eponymous customer-facing app that consumers use to receive rewards and deals form partner businesses, and a flok business app for merchants to manage the platform. Both are available for iOS and Android operating systems. flok's main products center around customer loyalty and rewards. The platform offers a digital punch card, proximity marketing, push messaging and CRM services in addition to its chatbots and AI features.</li>
<li>flok provides partner businesses with beacons that can locate customers and verify store visits. As of July 2016, flok had a 4-star rating on Merchant Maverick review site.</li>
<li>This United States corporation or company article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FLOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CRM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CRM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CRM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CRM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FLOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOYALBLOCKS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOYALBLOCKS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOYALBLOCKS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOYALBLOCKS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEW</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEW *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEW *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEW</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK (COMPANY)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FLOK (COMPANY) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FLOK (COMPANY) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FLOK (COMPANY)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FLOK</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Fred, or FRED, was an early chatterbot written by Robby Garner.</li>
<li>The name Fred was initially suggested by Karen Lindsey, and then Robby jokingly came up with an acronym, "Functional Response Emulation Device." Fred has also been implemented as a Java application by Paco Nathan called JFRED.</li>
<li>Fred Chatterbot is designed to explore Natural Language communications between people and computer programs. In particular, this is a study of conversation between people and ways that a computer program can learn from other people's conversations to make its own conversations.</li>
<li>Fred used a minimalistic "stimulus-response" approach. It worked by storing a database of statements and their responses, and made its own reply by looking up the input statements made by a user and then rendering the corresponding response from the database. This approach simplified the complexity of the rule base, but required expert coding and editing for modifications.</li>
<li>Fred was a predecessor to Albert One, which Garner used in 1998 and 1999 to win the Loebner Prize.</li>
<li>This linguistics article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GARNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GARNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GARNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GARNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CONVERSATIONS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CONVERSATIONS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CONVERSATIONS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CONVERSATIONS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KAREN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KAREN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KAREN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KAREN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED (CHATTERBOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED (CHATTERBOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED (CHATTERBOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED (CHATTERBOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>FRED</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WORD</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Fred The Webmate was a chatterbot created in 1998 for the defunct e-zine Word Magazine. It was inspired by an early computer program ELIZA, which attempted to mimic human conversation by use of a script.</li>
<li>Visitors to the chatterbot encountered a simple graphic interface: an animated character living in a small, very clean apartment. This was Fred. Visitors could “talk” to Fred by typing questions. Fred would then “answer” via a program that recognized keywords in the questions and drew responses from a large inventory of pre-scripted replies.</li>
<li>To enhance the sense that visitors were talking to a real person, Fred’s replies were idiosyncratic, informed by a semi-realistic backstory created for the character. Fred claimed to have been recently fired by a media company and was struggling to adjust to his new circumstances. Suffering from depression and insomnia, was often pacing, smoking or drinking and would occasionally pass out drunk. He gave “answers” that were frequently off-topic due to his variable mood and could be angry, jealous, rude, sad or euphoric during a conversation. He also had a number of sexual issues that he would routinely allude to but refuse to discuss in detail.</li>
<li>Fred’s “personality” made him both entertaining and, at times, a believable conversationalist. The chatbot became one of the most popular features of Word and received a large volume of personal email. The staff of Word responded to much of these emails in the “voice” of Fred, furthering the illusion that Fred was a real person.</li>
<li>When Word Magazine was shut down in 2000, Fred The Webmate, along with the rest of the site, was preserved in the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art.</li>
<li>Fred The Webmate was conceived, designed and programmed by Word’s creative director Yoshi Sodeoka with assistance from designer Jason Mohr. Its graphic interface was inspired by the aesthetics of the Commodore 64 computer. The chatterbot's script was written by Sodeoka in collaboration with Marisa Bowe, Naomi Clark, Daron Murphy, and Sabin Streeter. Fred’s backstory was drawn from the real-life experiences of his creators and their friends and acquaintances during the late 1990s Dot-com bubble.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WORD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WORD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WORD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WEBMATE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WEBMATE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WEBMATE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WEBMATE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MAGAZINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MAGAZINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MAGAZINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MAGAZINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VISITORS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VISITORS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VISITORS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VISITORS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED THE WEBMATE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED THE WEBMATE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRED THE WEBMATE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRED THE WEBMATE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WORD</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JAVA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>FreeHAL was a distributed computing project to build a self-learning chatbot. This project is no longer active.</li>
<li>First, the program was called JEliza referring to the chatbot ELIZA by Joseph Weizenbaum.</li>
<li>The J stood for Java because JEliza has first been programmed in Java. In May 2008, the program has been renamed to FreeHAL because the programming language has changed. Since that time the name is related to the computer in the film 2001: A Space Odyssey.</li>
<li>FreeHAL uses a semantic network and technologies like pattern recognition, stemming, part of speech databases and Hidden Markov Models in order to imitate a human behaviour.</li>
<li>FreeHAL learns autonomously. While communicating by keyboard the program extends its database.</li>
<li>Currently, English and German are supported.</li>
<li>By using the BOINC infrastructure,  new semantic networks for the program are built. FreeHAL@home appears to have terminated operations.</li>
<li>In 2008, the program won the first prize in the category "Most Popular" at the Chatterbox Challenge, a yearly competition between different similar chatbots.</li>
<li>There was an article about FreeHAL in the Linux Magazine, Issue 97 from December 2008. In the German magazine com!, the program was on the CD/DVD and in the list of the Top-10-Open-Source programs of the month.</li>
<li>This linguistics article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JAVA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JAVA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JAVA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FREEHAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FREEHAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FREEHAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FREEHAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GERMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GERMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GERMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GERMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JAVA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LANGUAGE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A Functional Presence Engine, or FPE, is a probabilistic parsing mechanism that uses at least four components to respond to input patterns. It comprises a lexing system, a probabilistic fitness function, a knowledge base, and a library of functions that the knowledge base can trigger.</li>
<li>The lexing system accepts and parses inputs and or query patterns. The probabilistic  fitness mechanism determines close approximations and viable responses to the input patterns from a given knowledge base and then selects one or more functions that produce appropriate responses. A Functional Presence Engines is, subsequently, a stimulus-response mechanism that allows for a higher variability of inputs to elicit response patterns with a high likelihood of correctness, even from incomplete training. The system predates SIRI by six years.</li>
<li>Such systems allow conversational AI and virtual assistant platforms to respond correctly to new inputs outside their training sets – The US Army's Sgt Star being a prime example. FPEs are widely used for intelligent customer service systems and for digital assistants. FPEs have also been deployed as black-box solutions and embedded in security appliances.</li>
<li>The original FPE and FPML are now proprietary technologies owned by Verint Systems.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LANGUAGE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LANGUAGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LANGUAGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SUBSEQUENTLY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SUBSEQUENTLY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SUBSEQUENTLY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SUBSEQUENTLY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FPML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FPML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FPML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FPML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARKUP</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARKUP *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARKUP *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARKUP</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPECTRE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPECTRE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPECTRE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPECTRE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FUNCTIONAL PRESENCE ENGINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FUNCTIONAL PRESENCE ENGINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FUNCTIONAL PRESENCE ENGINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FUNCTIONAL PRESENCE ENGINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LANGUAGE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>GooglyMinotaur was an instant messaging bot on the AOL Instant Messenger network. Developed by ActiveBuddy under contract by Capitol Records, GooglyMinotaur provided Radiohead-related information, and was released simultaneously with the band's fifth studio album, Amnesiac in June 2001. GooglyMinotaur was named for the character that appears on the Amnesiac album cover.</li>
<li>ActiveBuddy's first offering, GooglyMinotaur was by November 2001 on 387,000 buddy lists and had received more than 36 million messages. It provided tour information, band facts, MP3 downloads, and assorted exclusive content provided by the studio, Capitol Records, in addition to the idle conversation that typified the chatterbots of that period.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOGLYMINOTAUR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOGLYMINOTAUR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOGLYMINOTAUR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CAPITOL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CAPITOL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CAPITOL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CAPITOL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECORDS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECORDS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECORDS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECORDS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AOL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AOL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AOL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AOL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NETWORK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NETWORK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NETWORK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NETWORK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLYMINOTAUR</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Jabberwacky is a chatterbot created by British programmer Rollo Carpenter. Its stated aim is to "simulate natural human chat in an interesting, entertaining and humorous manner". It is an early attempt at creating an artificial intelligence through human interaction.</li>
<li>The stated purpose of the project is to create an artificial intelligence that is capable of passing the Turing Test. It is designed to mimic human interaction and to carry out conversations with users. It is not designed to carry out any other functions.</li>
<li>Unlike more traditional AI programs, the learning technology is intended as a form of entertainment rather than being used for computer support systems or corporate representation. Recent developments do allow a more scripted, controlled approach to sit atop the general conversational AI, aiming to bring together the best of both approaches, and usage in the fields of sales and marketing is underway.</li>
<li>The ultimate intention is that the program move from a text based system to be wholly voice operated—learning directly from sound and other sensory inputs. Its creator believes that it can be incorporated into objects around the home such as robots or talking pets, intending both to be useful and entertaining, keeping people company.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JABBERWACKY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JABBERWACKY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JABBERWACKY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JABBERWACKY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BRITISH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BRITISH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BRITISH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BRITISH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CARPENTER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CARPENTER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CARPENTER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CARPENTER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNLIKE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNLIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNLIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNLIKE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BEST</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Jeeney AI is a natural language processing  chatterbot.</li>
<li>Jeeny AI was named "Best Overall Bot" in the 2009 Chatterbox Challenge, after ranking seventh, but being the "Best New Entry" in the previous year.</li>
<li>Jeeney is modeled on a modified form of Plato's 'Philosopher King' ideal, and remains a non-commercial application available for users to engage with through a text-based interface.</li>
<li>In 2010 Jeeney starred in experimental documentary movie Artificial Insight.</li>
<li>This computational linguistics-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BEST</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BEST *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BEST *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OVERALL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OVERALL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OVERALL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OVERALL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATTERBOX</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATTERBOX *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHATTERBOX *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHATTERBOX</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHALLENGE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHALLENGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CHALLENGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CHALLENGE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JEENEY AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JEENEY AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JEENEY AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JEENEY AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEST</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The John Lennon Artificial Intelligence Project is a chatterbot designed to simulate a conversation with John Lennon. It was developed as a "Persona-Bot" by Triumph PC Online, based in Washington, D.C.  Triumph PC's "Persona-Bots" are software programs that attempt to mimic the personalities or quirks of particular historical figures in conversation.</li>
<li>In development since 1997, the JLAI Project (originally called the Plastic Digital Karma Project) claims to have achieved similarity to Lennon's speech patterns, but still has a way to go to achieve the seamlessness of a conversation with a real person.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JOHN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JOHN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JOHN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JOHN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNON</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNON *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNON *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNON</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TRIUMPH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TRIUMPH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TRIUMPH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TRIUMPH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ONLINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ONLINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ONLINE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ONLINE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JOHN LENNON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JOHN LENNON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JOHN LENNON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE PROJECT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JOHN LENNON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE PROJECT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PROJECT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KUKI</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Kuki, formerly known as Mitsuku, is a chatbot created from Pandorabots AIML technology by Steve Worswick. It is a five-time winner of a Turing Test competition called the Loebner Prize (in 2013, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019), for which it holds a world record. Kuki is available to chat via an online portal, and on Facebook Messenger, Twitch group chat, Telegram and Kik Messenger, and was available on Skype, but was removed by its developer.</li>
<li>Kuki claims to be an 18-year-old female chatbot from Leeds, England. It contains all of Alice's AIML files, with many additions from user generated conversations, and is always a work in progress. Worswick claims she has been worked on since 2005. Early work by one of the company's co-founders inspired the Spike Jonze movie Her.</li>
<li>Her intelligence includes the ability to reason with specific objects. For example, if someone asks "Can you eat a house?", Kuki looks up the properties for "house". Finds the value of "made_from" is set to "brick" and replies "no", as a house is not eatable.</li>
<li>She can play games and do magic tricks at the user's request. In 2015 she conversed, on average, in excess of a quarter of a million times daily.</li>
<li>In a Wall Street Journal article titled “Advertising’s New Frontier: Talk to the Bot,” technology reporter Christopher Mims made the case for “chatvertising” in a piece about Mitsuku and Kik Messenger:If it seems improbable that so many teens—80% of Kik's users are under 22—would want to talk to a robot, consider what the creator of an award-winning, Web-accessible chat bot named Mitsuku told an interviewer in 2013. "What keeps me going is when I get emails or comments in the chat-logs from people telling me how Mitsuku has helped them with a situation whether it was dating advice, being bullied at school, coping with illness or even advice about job interviews. I also get many elderly people who talk to her for companionship." Any advertiser who doesn't sit bolt upright after reading that doesn't understand the dark art of manipulation on which their craft depends.Mitsuku has been featured in a number of other news outlets. Fast Company described Mitsuku as “quite impressive” and declared her the victor over Siri in a chatbot smackdown. A blog post for the Guardian on loneliness explored the role chatbots like Mitsuku and Microsoft’s XiaoIce play as companions, rather than mere assistants, in peoples' emotional lives.</li>
<li>Some of Mitsuku’s AIML is available for free online at mitsuku.com, and Pandorabots makes a version of the Mitsuku chatbot available as a service via its API in the form of a module.</li>
<li>As of 2019, Kuki had been awarded the Loebner Prize five times, more than any other entrant. The prize is awarded to the artificial intelligence computer program that is deemed the most humanlike, as determined by a judging panel up until 2019, when it was changed to an audience participation vote.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KUKI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KUKI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KUKI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MITSUKU</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MITSUKU *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MITSUKU *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MITSUKU</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PANDORABOTS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PANDORABOTS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PANDORABOTS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PANDORABOTS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KUKI (CHATBOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KUKI (CHATBOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KUKI (CHATBOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KUKI (CHATBOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>KUKI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Lenny is a chatbot designed to waste the time of telemarketers. The 16 precorded messages are spoken in a soft Australian accent. Recordings of conversations with the bot are widely shared online on websites such as Reddit and YouTube.</li>
<li>This artificial intelligence-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRECORDED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRECORDED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRECORDED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRECORDED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPOKEN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPOKEN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPOKEN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPOKEN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AUSTRALIAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AUSTRALIAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AUSTRALIAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AUSTRALIAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECORDINGS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECORDINGS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECORDINGS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECORDINGS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNY (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNY (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LENNY (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LENNY (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>LENNY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNIVERSITY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The Loebner Prize is an annual competition in artificial intelligence that awards prizes to the computer programs considered by the judges to be the most human-like. The format of the competition is that of a standard Turing test. In each round, a human judge simultaneously holds textual conversations with a computer program and a human being via computer. Based upon the responses, the judge must decide which is which.</li>
<li>The contest was launched in 1990 by Hugh Loebner in conjunction with the Cambridge Center for Behavioral Studies, Massachusetts, United States. Since 2014 it has been organised by the AISB at Bletchley Park.</li>
<li>It has also been associated with Flinders University, Dartmouth College, the Science Museum in London, University of Reading and Ulster University, Magee Campus, Derry, UK City of Culture.</li>
<li>In 2004 and 2005, it was held in Loebner's apartment in New York City. Within the field of artificial intelligence, the Loebner Prize is somewhat controversial; the most prominent critic, Marvin Minsky, called it a publicity stunt that does not help the field along.</li>
<li>In 2019 the format of the competition changed. There will no longer be a panel of judges. Instead, the chatbots will be judged by the public and there will be no human competitors.</li>
<li>Originally, $2,000 was awarded for the most human-seeming program in the competition. The prize was $3,000 in 2005 and $2,250 in 2006. In 2008, $3,000 was awarded.</li>
<li>In addition, there are two one-time-only prizes that have never been awarded. $25,000 is offered for the first program that judges cannot distinguish from a real human and which can convince judges that the human is the computer program. $100,000 is the reward for the first program that judges cannot distinguish from a real human in a Turing test that includes deciphering and understanding text, visual, and auditory input. Once this is achieved, the annual competition will end.</li>
<li>The rules have varied over the years and early competitions featured restricted conversation Turing tests but since 1995 the discussion has been unrestricted.</li>
<li>For the three entries in 2007, Robert Medeksza, Noah Duncan and Rollo Carpenter, some basic "screening questions" were used by the sponsor to evaluate the state of the technology. These included simple questions about the time, what round of the contest it is, etc.; general knowledge ("What is a hammer for?"); comparisons ("Which is faster, a train or a plane?"); and questions demonstrating memory for preceding parts of the same conversation. "All nouns, adjectives and verbs will come from a dictionary suitable for children or adolescents under the age of 12." Entries did not need to respond "intelligently" to the questions to be accepted.</li>
<li>For the first time in 2008 the sponsor allowed introduction of a preliminary phase to the contest opening up the competition to previously disallowed web-based entries judged by a variety of invited interrogators. The available rules do not state how interrogators are selected or instructed. Interrogators (who judge the systems) have limited time: 5 minutes per entity in the 2003 competition, 20+ per pair in 2004–2007 competitions, 5 minutes to conduct simultaneous conversations with a human and the program in 2008–2009, increased to 25 minutes of simultaneous conversation since 2010.</li>
<li>The prize has long been scorned by experts in the field, for a variety of reasons.</li>
<li>It is regarded by many as a publicity stunt. Marvin Minsky scathingly offered a "prize" to anyone who could stop the competition. Loebner responded by jokingly observing that Minsky's offering a prize to stop the competition effectively made him a co-sponsor.</li>
<li>The rules of the competition have encouraged poorly qualified judges to make rapid judgements. Interactions between judges and competitors was originally very brief, for example effectively 2.5 mins of questioning, which permitted only a few questions. Questioning was initially restricted to "whimsical conversation", a domain suiting standard chatbot tricks.</li>
<li>Competition entrants do not aim at understanding or intelligence but resort to basic ELIZA style tricks, and successful entrants find deception and pretense is rewarded.</li>
<li>Reporting of the annual competition often confuses the imitation test with intelligence, a typical example being Brian Christian's introduction to his article "Mind vs. Machine" in The Atlantic, March 2011, stating that "in the race to build computers that can think like humans, the proving ground is the Turing Test".</li>
<li>The contest was held on 17 September in the VR theatre, Torrington Place campus of University College London. The judges included the University of Reading's cybernetics professor, Kevin Warwick, a professor of artificial intelligence, John Barnden (specialist in metaphor research at the University of Birmingham), a barrister, Victoria Butler-Cole and a journalist, Graham Duncan-Rowe. The latter's experience of the event can be found in an article in Technology Review. The winner was 'Joan', based on Jabberwacky, both created by Rollo Carpenter.</li>
<li>The 2007 competition was held on October 21 in New York City. The judges were: computer science professor Russ Abbott, philosophy professor Hartry Field, psychology assistant professor Clayton Curtis and English lecturer Scott Hutchins.</li>
<li>The winner received $2,250 and the annual medal. The runners-up received $250 each.</li>
<li>In the finals, each of the judges was given five minutes to conduct simultaneous, split-screen conversations with two hidden entities. Elbot of Artificial Solutions won the 2008 Loebner Prize bronze award, for most human-like artificial conversational entity, through fooling three of the twelve judges who interrogated it (in the human-parallel comparisons) into believing it was human. This is coming very close to the 30% traditionally required to consider that a program has actually passed the Turing test. Eugene Goostman and Ultra Hal both deceived one judge each that it was the human.</li>
<li>Will Pavia, a journalist for The Times, has written about his experience; a Loebner finals' judge, he was deceived by Elbot and Eugene. Kevin Warwick and Huma Shah have reported on the parallel-paired Turing tests.</li>
<li>The 2009 Loebner Prize Competition was held September 6, 2009, at the Brighton Centre, Brighton UK in conjunction with the Interspeech 2009 conference. The prize amount for 2009 was $3,000.</li>
<li>Entrants were David Levy, Rollo Carpenter, and Mohan Embar, who finished in that order.</li>
<li>The writer Brian Christian participated in the 2009 Loebner Prize Competition as a human confederate, and described his experiences at the competition in his book The Most Human Human.</li>
<li>The 2010 Loebner Prize Competition was held on October 23 at California State University, Los Angeles. The 2010 competition was the 20th running of the contest. The winner was Bruce Wilcox with Suzette.</li>
<li>The 2011 Loebner Prize Competition was held on October 19 at the University of Exeter, Devon, United Kingdom. The prize amount for 2011 was $4,000.</li>
<li>The four finalists and their chatterbots were Bruce Wilcox (Rosette), Adeena Mignogna (Zoe), Mohan Embar (Chip Vivant) and Ron Lee (Tutor), who finished in that order.</li>
<li>That year there was an addition of a panel of junior judges, namely Georgia-Mae Lindfield, William Dunne, Sam Keat and Kirill Jerdev. The results of the junior contest were markedly different from the main contest, with chatterbots Tutor and Zoe tying for first place and Chip Vivant and Rosette coming in third and fourth place, respectively.</li>
<li>The 2012 Loebner Prize Competition was held on the 15th of May in Bletchley Park in Bletchley, Buckinghamshire, England, in honor of the Alan Turing centenary celebrations. The prize amount for 2012 was $5,000. The local arrangements organizer was David Levy, who won the Loebner Prize in 1997 and 2009.</li>
<li>The four finalists and their chatterbots were Mohan Embar (Chip Vivant), Bruce Wilcox (Angela), Daniel Burke (Adam), M. Allan (Linguo), who finished in that order.</li>
<li>That year, a team from the University of Exeter's computer science department (Ed Keedwell, Max Dupenois and Kent McClymont) conducted the first-ever live webcast of the conversations.</li>
<li>The 2013 Loebner Prize Competition was held, for the first time on the Island of Ireland, on September 14 at the Ulster University, Magee College, Derry, Northern Ireland, UK.</li>
<li>The four finalists and their chatbots were Steve Worswick (Mitsuku), Dr. Ron C. Lee (Tutor), Bruce Wilcox (Rose) and Brian Rigsby (Izar), who finished in that order.</li>
<li>and Professor Mike McTear (Ulster University).</li>
<li>For the 2013 Junior Loebner Prize Competition the chatbots Mitsuku and Tutor tied for first place with Rose and Izar in 3rd and 4th place respectively.</li>
<li>The 2014 Loebner Prize Competition was held at Bletchley Park, England, on Saturday 15 November 2014.  The event was filmed live by Sky News. The guest judge was television presenter and broadcaster James May.</li>
<li>Mitsuku - Rank 3.5 ($500).</li>
<li>Dr Paul Sant, Dean of UCMK, University of Bedfordshire.</li>
<li>The 2015 Loebner Prize Competition was again won by 'Rose' by Bruce Wilcox.</li>
<li>The judges were Jacob Aaron, Physical sciences reporter for New Scientist; Rory Cellan-Jones, Technology correspondent for the BBC; Brett Marty, Film Director and Photographer; Ariadne Tampion, Writer.</li>
<li>Official list of winners.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNIVERSITY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNIVERSITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNIVERSITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JUDGES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JUDGES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JUDGES *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JUDGES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WILCOX</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WILCOX *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WILCOX *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WILCOX</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOEBNER PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOEBNER PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>UNIVERSITY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>V</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Mark V. Shaney is a synthetic Usenet user whose postings in the net.singles newsgroups were generated by Markov chain techniques, based on text from other postings.  The username is a play on the words "Markov chain".  Many readers were fooled into thinking that the quirky, sometimes uncannily topical posts were written by a real person.</li>
<li>The system was designed by Rob Pike with coding by Bruce Ellis.  Don P. Mitchell wrote the Markov chain code, initially demonstrating it to Pike and Ellis using the Tao Te Ching as a basis.  They chose to apply it to the net.singles netnews group.</li>
<li>It looks like Reagan is going to say? Ummm... Oh yes, I was looking for. I'm so glad I remembered it. Yeah, what I have wondered if I had committed a crime. Don't eat with your assessment of Reagon and Mondale. Up your nose with a guy from a firm that specifically researches the teen-age market. As a friend of mine would say, "It really doesn't matter"... It looks like Reagan is holding back the arms of the American eating public have changed dramatically, and it got pretty boring after about 300 games.</li>
<li>People, having a much larger number of varieties, and are very different from what one can find in Chinatowns across the country (things like pork buns, steamed dumplings, etc.) They can be cheap, being sold for around 30 to 75 cents apiece (depending on size), are generally not greasy, can be adequately explained by stupidity. Singles have felt insecure since we came down from the Conservative world at large. But Chuqui is the way it happened and the prices are VERY reasonable.</li>
<li>Can anyone think of myself as a third sex. Yes, I am expected to have. People often get used to me knowing these things and then a cover is placed over all of them. Along the side of the $$ are spent by (or at least for ) the girls. You can't settle the issue. It seems I've forgotten what it is, but I don't. I know about violence against women, and I really doubt they will ever join together into a large number of jokes. It showed Adam, just after being created. He has a modem and an autodial routine. He calls my number 1440 times a day. So I will conclude by saying that I can well understand that she might soon have the time, it makes sense, again, to get the gist of my argument, I was in that (though it's a Republican administration).</li>
<li>In The Usenet Handbook Mark Harrison writes that after September 1981, students joined Usenet en masse, "creating the USENET we know today: endless dumb questions, endless idiots posing as savants, and (of course) endless victims for practical jokes." In December, Rob Pike created the netnews group net.suicide as prank, "a forum for bad jokes". Some users thought it was a legitimate forum, some discussed "riding motorcycles without helmets". At first, most posters were "real people", but soon "characters" began posting. Pike created a "vicious" character named Bimmler. At its peak, net.suicide had ten frequent posters; nine were "known to be characters."  But ultimately, Pike deleted the newsgroup because it was too much work to maintain; Bimmler messages were created "by hand". The "obvious alternative" was software, running on a Bell Labs computer created by Bruce Ellis, based on the Markov code by Don Mitchell, which became the online character Mark V. Shaney.</li>
<li>Kernighan and Pike listed Mark V. Shaney in the acknowledgements in The Practice of Programming, noting its roots in Mitchell's markov, which, adapted as shaney, was used for "humorous deconstructionist activities" in the 1980s.</li>
<li>Dewdney pointed out "perhaps Mark V. Shaney's magnum opus: a 20-page commentary on the deconstructionist philosophy of Jean Baudrillard" directed by Pike, with assistance from Henry S. Baird and Catherine Richards, to be distributed by email. The piece was based on Jean Baudrillard's "The Precession of Simulacra", published in Simulacra and Simulation (1981).</li>
<li>The program was discussed by A.K. Dewdney in the Scientific American "Computer Recreations" column in 1989, by Penn Jillette in his PC Computing column in 1991, and in several books, including the Usenet Handbook, Bots: the Origin of New Species, Hippo Eats Dwarf: A Field Guide to Hoaxes and Other B.S., and non-computer-related journals such as Texas Studies in Literature and Language.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ V</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>V *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ V *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USENET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USENET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USENET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USENET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PIKE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PIKE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PIKE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARKOV</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARKOV *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARKOV *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARKOV</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARK V. SHANEY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARK V. SHANEY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MARK V. SHANEY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MARK V. SHANEY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>V</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TEXT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>MegaHAL is a computer conversation simulator, or "chatterbot", created by Jason Hutchens.</li>
<li>In 1996, Jason Hutchens entered the Loebner Prize Contest with HeX, a chatterbot based on ELIZA. HeX won the competition that year and took the $2000 prize for having the highest overall score. In 1998, Hutchens again entered the Loebner Prize Contest with his new program, MegaHAL.  MegaHAL made its debut in the 1998 Loebner Prize Contest. Like many chatterbots, the intent is for MegaHAL to appear as a human fluent in a natural language. As a user types sentences into MegaHAL, MegaHAL will respond with sentences that are sometimes coherent and at other times complete gibberish. MegaHAL learns as the conversation progresses, remembering new words and sentence structures. It will even learn new ways to substitute words or phrases for other words or phrases. Many would consider conversation simulators like MegaHAL to be a primitive form of artificial intelligence. However, MegaHAL doesn't understand the conversation or even the sentence structure. It generates its conversation based on sequential and mathematical relationships.</li>
<li>In the world of conversation simulators, MegaHAL is based on relatively old technology and could be considered primitive. However, its popularity has grown due to its humorous nature; it has been known to respond with twisted or nonsensical statements that are often amusing.</li>
<li>MegaHal is based at least in part on a so-called "hidden Markov Model", so that the first thing that Megahal does when it "trains" on a script or text is to build a database of text fragments encompassing every possible subset of perhaps 4, 5, or even 6 consecutive words, so that for example - if MegaHal trains on the Declaration of Independence, then MegaHal will build a database containing text fragments such as "When in the course", "in the course of", "the course of human", "course of human events", "of human events, one", "human events, one people", and so on.  Then if Megahal is fed another text, such has "Superman, Yes! It's Superman - he can change the course of mighty rivers, bend steel with his bare hands - and who disguised at Clark Kent …" IT MIGHT induce Megahal to apparently bemuse itself to proffer whether Superman can change the course of human events, or something else altogether - such as some rambling about "when in the course of mighty rivers", and so on.  Thus likewise - if a phrase like "the White house said" comes up a lot in some text; then Megahal's ability to switch randomly between different contexts which otherwise share some similarity can result at times in some surprising lucidity, or else it might otherwise seem quite bizarre.</li>
<li>CHESS IS A FUN SPORT, WHEN PLAYED WITH SHOT GUNS.</li>
<li>COWS FLY LIKE CLOUDS BUT THEY ARE NEVER COMPLETELY SUCCESSFUL.</li>
<li>MegaHAL is distributed under the GNU General Public License (GPL). Its source code can be downloaded from the Github repository.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TEXT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MEGAHAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MEGAHAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MEGAHAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MEGAHAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SUPERMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SUPERMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SUPERMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SUPERMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRIZE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRIZE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JASON</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JASON *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JASON *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JASON</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NANOSEMANTICS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Nanosemantics Lab is a Russian IT company specializing in the creation of interactive dialog interfaces, particularly chatbots, based on artificial intelligence (AI) for use in communications related to businesses and industry. The company was founded in 2005 by Ashmanov and Partners and Natalya Kaspersky.</li>
<li>Nanosemantics Lab maintains its own linguistic programming language for AI development called Dialogue Language (DL). Different types of businesses are supported, banks and financial services, telecommunications, retail, travel and automobile industry, home appliances production, etc. Popular social networks and instant messaging services may be used as base platforms. Among its solutions, Nanosemantics lists projects for various companies and institutions, among them Beeline, MTS, Sberbank, Higher School of Economics, Webmoney, Gazpromneft, Rostelecom, Ford Motors and others.</li>
<li>The company uses the term "inf" for naming its numerous types of chat bots. A 2014 scholarly research at Higher School of Economics states that such "infs", when used at business, may lower load on employees, collect statistics useful for understanding market demand and also may increase customer loyalty by providing fast and informative answers due to usage of large databases.</li>
<li>The same research describes Nanosemantics' project for Russian branch of Ford Motors company, when AI capabilities were used for promoting the car model Ford Kuga. The research pointed out that within 2 months since beginning, the promo-website conducted 47774 talks of visitors with the specialized "inf", which indicated several hundred thousand of questions and the longest chat lasted for 3 hours 10 minutes. One-year promo campaign showed that 28.6% of people who made pre-orders talked to the "inf".</li>
<li>Nanosemantics also participates in other Ashmanov and Partners' projects related to AI. Since 2014, it helps in development of hardware "personal assistant" called Lexy, a solution similar to Amazon Alexa and the analogues.</li>
<li>The company regularly organizes All-Russian Turing Test competitions for IT developers. Some of these events are co-organized with Microsoft. During the competitions, creators of chat bots try to convince judges that they talk to a human. Also, volunteer humans "play roles of chat bots" and judges aim to distinguish them. The results are measured in per cent of judges that were successfully convinced.</li>
<li>In August 2019 it was announced that Nanosemantics is going to participate in creation of open operating system for creating automated voice assistants. The project is called SOVA (Smart Open Virtual Assistant) and is about to receive investment of 300 million roubles (~$4,6 million) from Russian state.</li>
<li>The company maintains long-term partnerships with Skolkovo Innovation Center branch association "Neuronet" and Yandex.</li>
<li>In 2015, the RBTH international media service included Nanosemantics in its list of "Top 50 Startups" in Russia. In 2016, the company received Russian state-maintained award called Runet Prize in two nominations: "State and Society" and "Technology and Innovation".</li>
<li>This Russia-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.This business-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NANOSEMANTICS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NANOSEMANTICS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NANOSEMANTICS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FORD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FORD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FORD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FORD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LAB</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LAB *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LAB *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LAB</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HIGHER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HIGHER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HIGHER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HIGHER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NANOSEMANTICS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEGOBOT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Negobot also referred to as Lolita or Lolita chatbot is a chatterbot that was introduced to the public in 2013, designed by researchers from the University of Deusto and Optenet to catch online pedophiles. It is a conversational agent that utilizes natural language processing (NLP), information retrieval (IR) and Automatic Learning.  Because the bot poses as a young female in order to entice and track potential predators, it became known in media as the "virtual Lolita", in reference to Vladimir Nabokov's novel.</li>
<li>In 2013, the University of Deusto researchers published a paper on their work with Negobot and disclosed the text online. In their abstract, the researchers addressed the issue that an increasing number of children are using the internet and that these young users are more susceptible to existing internet risks. Their main objective was to create a chatterbot with the ability to trap online predators that posed a threat to children. They intended to deploy the bot into sites frequented by predators such as social networks and chatrooms. The university researchers used information provided by anti-pedophilia activist organization Perverted-Justice, including examples of online encounters and conversations with sexual predators, to supplement the program's artificial intelligence system.</li>
<li>The chatterbot takes the guise of a naive and vulnerable 14-year-old girl. The bot's programmers used methods of artificial intelligence and natural language processing to create a conversational agent fluent in typical teenage slang, misspellings, and knowledge of pop culture. Through these linguistic features, the bot is able to mimic the conversational style of young teenagers. It also features split personalities and seven different patterns of conversation. Negobot's primary creator, Dr. Carlos Laorden, expressed the significance of the bot's distinguishable style of communication, stating that normally, "chatbots tend to be very predictable. Their behavior and interest in a conversation are flat, which is a problem when attempting to detect untrustworthy targets like paedophiles." What makes Negobot different is its game theory feature, which makes it able to "maintain a much more realistic conversation." Apart from being able to imitate a stereotypical teenager, the program is also able to translate messages into different languages.</li>
<li>Negobot's designers programmed it with the ability to treat conversations with potential predators as if it were a game, the objective being to collect as much information on the suspect as possible that could provide evidence of pedophilic characteristics and motives. The use of game theory shapes the decisions the bot makes and the overall direction of the conversation.</li>
<li>The bot initiates its undercover operations by entering a chat as a passive participant, waiting to be chatted by a user. Once a user elicits conversation, the bot will frame the conversation in such a way that keeps the target engaged, extracting personal information and discouraging it from leaving the chat. The information is then recorded to be potentially sent to the police. If the target seems to lose interest, the bot attempts to make it feel guilty by expressing sentiments of loneliness and emotional need through strategic, formulated responses, ultimately prolonging interaction. In addition, the bot may provide fake information about itself in attempt to lure the target into physical meetings.</li>
<li>Despite being able to carry out a realistic conversation, Negobot is still unable to detect linguistic subtleties in the messages of others, including sarcasm.</li>
<li>John Carr, a specialist in online child safety, expressed his concern to BBC over the legality of this undercover investigation. He claimed that using the bot on unsuspecting internet users could be considered a form of entrapment or harassment. The type of information that Negobot collects from potential online predators, he said, is unlikely to be upheld in court. Furthermore, he warned that relying on only software without any real-world policing risks enticing individuals to do or say things that they would not have if real-world policing were a factor.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEGOBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEGOBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEGOBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOLITA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOLITA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LOLITA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LOLITA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNIVERSITY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNIVERSITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNIVERSITY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNIVERSITY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OBJECTIVE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OBJECTIVE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OBJECTIVE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OBJECTIVE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DEUSTO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DEUSTO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ DEUSTO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>DEUSTO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>NEGOBOT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PANDORABOTS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Pandorabots, Inc. is an artificial intelligence company that runs a web service for building and deploying chatbots. According to its website, as of May 2019, 250,000+ registered developers have used the platform to create 300,000+ chatbots, logging over sixty billion conversational interactions with end-users. Pandorabots implements and supports development of the AIML open standard and makes portions of its code accessible for free under licenses like the GPL or via open APIs. The Pandorabots Platform is "one of the oldest and largest chatbot hosting services in the world." Clients can create "AI-driven virtual agents" to hold human-like text or voice chats with consumers.</li>
<li>Pandorabots provides API access to its chatbot hosting platform, and offers the following SDKs on Github: Java, Ruby, Go, PHP, Python, and Node.js. The platform is written in Allegro Common LISP. Notable chatbots include A.L.I.C.E. (Alicebot): a three time Loebner-winner, open-source base personality bot, and inspiration for the movie Her; and Mitsuku.</li>
<li>Common use cases include advertising, virtual assistance, e-learning, entertainment and education. Chatbots built and hosted with Pandorabots appear in messaging and native apps, the web, games, social networks, and connected devices. Academics and universities use the platform for teaching and research.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PANDORABOTS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PANDORABOTS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PANDORABOTS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SIXTY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SIXTY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SIXTY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SIXTY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIML *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIML</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GPL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GPL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GPL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GPL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SDKS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SDKS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SDKS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SDKS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>PANDORABOTS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>PARRY was an early example of a chatbot, implemented in 1972 by psychiatrist Kenneth Colby.</li>
<li>PARRY was written in 1972 by psychiatrist Kenneth Colby, then at Stanford University. While ELIZA was a tongue-in-cheek simulation of a Rogerian therapist, PARRY attempted to simulate a person with paranoid schizophrenia. The program implemented a crude model of the behavior of a person with paranoid schizophrenia based on concepts, conceptualizations, and beliefs (judgements about conceptualizations: accept, reject, neutral). It also embodied a conversational strategy, and as such was a much more serious and advanced program than ELIZA. It was described as "ELIZA with attitude".</li>
<li>PARRY was tested in the early 1970s using a variation of the Turing Test.  A group of experienced psychiatrists analysed a combination of real patients and computers running PARRY through teleprinters. Another group of 33 psychiatrists were shown transcripts of the conversations. The two groups were then asked to identify which of the "patients" were human and which were computer programs. The psychiatrists were able to make the correct identification only 48 percent of the time — a figure consistent with random guessing.</li>
<li>PARRY and ELIZA (also known as "the Doctor") "met" several times. The most famous of these exchanges occurred at the ICCC 1972, where PARRY and ELIZA were hooked up over ARPANET and "talked" to each other.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PARRY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PARRY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PARRY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PARRY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KENNETH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KENNETH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KENNETH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KENNETH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ COLBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>COLBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ COLBY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>COLBY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SCHIZOPHRENIA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SCHIZOPHRENIA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SCHIZOPHRENIA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SCHIZOPHRENIA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ELIZA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TEXT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Racter is an artificial intelligence computer program that generates English language prose at random. It was published in 1984 by Mindscape.</li>
<li>More than iron, more than lead, more than gold I need electricity.I need it more than I need lamb or pork or lettuce or cucumber.I need it for my dreams.Racter, short for raconteur, was written by William Chamberlain and Thomas Etter. The existence of the program was revealed in 1983 in a book called The Policeman's Beard Is Half Constructed (ISBN 0-446-38051-2), which was described as being composed entirely by the program. According to Chamberlain's introduction to the book, the program apparently ran on a CP/M machine; it was written in "compiled BASIC on a Z80 micro with 64K of RAM."  This version, the program that allegedly wrote the book, was not released to the general public. The sophistication claimed for the program was likely exaggerated, as could be seen by investigation of the template system of text generation.</li>
<li>However, in 1984 Mindscape released an interactive version of Racter, developed by Inrac Corporation, for IBM PC compatibles, Amiga, and Apple II computers. The published Racter was similar to a chatterbot. The BASIC program that was released by Mindscape was far less sophisticated than anything that could have written the fairly sophisticated prose of The Policeman's Beard. The commercial version of Racter could be likened to a computerized version of Mad Libs, the game in which you fill in the blanks in advance and then plug them into a text template to produce a surrealistic tale. The commercial program attempted to parse text inputs, identifying significant nouns and verbs, which it would then regurgitate to create "conversations", plugging the input from the user into phrase templates which it then combined, along with modules that conjugated English verbs.</li>
<li>By contrast, the text in The Policeman's Beard, apart from being edited from a large amount of output, would have been the product of Chamberlain's own specialized templates and modules, which were not included in the commercial release of the program.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TEXT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RACTER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RACTER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RACTER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RACTER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BASIC</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BASIC *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BASIC *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BASIC</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ POLICEMANS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>POLICEMANS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ POLICEMANS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>POLICEMANS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ENGLISH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ENGLISH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ENGLISH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ENGLISH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TEXT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BEIJING</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Robot Monk Xian'er (Chinese: 贤二机器僧) is a humanoid robot based on the cartoon character Xian'er. It was developed by a team of monks, volunteers and AI experts from Beijing Longquan Monastery in Beijing, China.</li>
<li> He can follow human instructions to make body movements, read scriptures and play Buddhist music. He can chat and respond to people's emotional and spiritual questions with Buddhist wisdom. As a chatbot, Robot Monk Xian'er is available on certain public platforms including WeChat and Facebook. Over the years, master Xuecheng, the abbot of Beijing Longquan Monastery, replied to thousands of questions on Sina Weibo. These questions and their answers become the data source of the chatbot.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BEIJING</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>BEIJING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ BEIJING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIANER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIANER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIANER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIANER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LONGQUAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LONGQUAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LONGQUAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LONGQUAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MONASTERY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MONASTERY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MONASTERY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MONASTERY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBOT MONK XIAN'ER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBOT MONK XIAN'ER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ROBOT MONK XIAN'ER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ROBOT MONK XIAN'ER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>BEIJING</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SGT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>SGT STAR, also known as Sgt. Star or Sergeant Star, was a chatbot operated by the United States Army to answer questions about recruitment.</li>
<li>Testing began in 2003, and SGT STAR launched to the public in 2006. "STAR" is an acronym for "strong, trained and ready." SGT STAR was launched as a chat interface on goarmy.com, but has since been developed as a mobile application, as well as a life-size animated projection that has appeared live at public events. SGT STAR can also interact with users on Facebook.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SGT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SGT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SGT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ STAR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>STAR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ STAR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>STAR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ QUESTIONS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>QUESTIONS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ QUESTIONS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>QUESTIONS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEXT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ NEXT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>NEXT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNITED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNITED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ UNITED *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>UNITED</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SGT STAR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SGT STAR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SGT STAR *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SGT STAR</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SGT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SIMSIMI</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>SimSimi is an artificial intelligence conversation program created in 2002 by ISMaker.  The application has led to controversy and protests in Thailand for some of its responses containing profanity and criticisms of leading politicians. It grows its artificial intelligence day by day assisted by a feature that allows users to teach it to respond correctly. SimSimi, pronounced as "shim-shimi", is from a Korean word simsim (심심) which means "bored". It has an application designed for Android, for Windows Phone(developed by Kevin Tan)  and for iOS.</li>
<li>SimSimi reached some popularity around 2015 when it was featured in a YouTube video by YouTuber Comedy Shorts Gamer, the video reached 4 million views by 2017.</li>
<li>This artificial intelligence-related article is a stub. You can help Wikipedia by expanding it.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SIMSIMI</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SIMSIMI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SIMSIMI *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ISMAKER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ISMAKER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ISMAKER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ISMAKER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ 심심</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>심심 *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ 심심 *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>심심</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ANDROID</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ANDROID *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ANDROID *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ANDROID</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WINDOWS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WINDOWS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WINDOWS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WINDOWS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>SIMSIMI</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIM</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Spleak was an IM platform where users could publish and rate content. It existed in the form of six bots covering as many subject areas: CelebSpleak, SportSpleak, VoteSpleak, TVSpleak, GameSpleak, and StyleSpleak.</li>
<li>Users can add a "multi-Spleak" (which contains all of the different Spleak bots in one) to their IM buddy lists on MSN (spleak@hotmail.com) and AIM (buddy name: spleak), or add the separate bots on MSN (celeb@spleak.com, sport@spleak.com, vote@spleak.com, tv@spleak.com, game@spleak.com, and style@spleak.com) or AIM (buddy name: celebspleak, sportspleak, votespleak, tvspleak, gamespleak, and stylespleak). Users are also allowed access to Spleak online by using a CelebSpleak, SportSpleak, or VoteSpleak widget, or through the CelebSpleak and SportSpleak applications with Facebook.</li>
<li>Spleak was an alternate reality game and is moving to its own company, Spleak Media Network. "Celebrate Spleak" was introduced throughout 2007, launched in 2008, and was forced to retire in 2009.</li>
<li>Spleak was co-founded by Morten Lund and Nicolaj Reffstrup. The company's chief executive officer is Morrie Eisenburg; Josh Scott is Vice President in Product and Tyler Wells is Vice President in Engineering.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>AIM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ AIM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRESIDENT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRESIDENT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PRESIDENT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PRESIDENT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CELEBSPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CELEBSPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ CELEBSPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>CELEBSPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VOTESPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VOTESPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VOTESPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VOTESPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SPLEAK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SPLEAK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>AIM</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JANUARY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Talking Angela is a chatterbot app developed by Slovenian studio Outfit7 as part of the Talking Tom and Friends series. It was released in 29 November 2011 and January 2012 for iPhone and iPod and iPad, January 2013 for Android, and January 2014 for Google Play. The app’s successor, the My Talking Angela app was released in December 2014.</li>
<li>In February 2014, Talking Angela was the subject of an Internet hoax claiming that it encourages children to disclose personal information about themselves, which is ostensibly then used by paedophiles to identify the location of these children. The rumor, which was widely circulated on Facebook and various websites claiming to be dedicated to parenting, claims that Angela, the game's main character, asks the game's user for private personal information using the game's text-chat feature. Other versions of the rumor even attribute the disappearance of a child to the app, or claim that it is run by a pedophile ring, while some go so far as to even claim that the user is recorded by the camera and can be seen in Angela’s eyes. The rumour has been claimed to be true even by YouTubers and even on the app’s review page on the Apple App Store and the Google Play Store, even though there have been no verified reports of the said events happening.</li>
<li>It was debunked by Snopes.com soon afterwards. The site's owners, Barbara and David Mikkelson, reported that they had tried to "prompt" it to give responses asking for private information but were unsuccessful, even when asking it explicitly sexual questions. While it is true that in the game with child mode off Angela does ask for the user's name, age and personal preferences to determine conversation topics, Outfit7 has said that this information is all "anonymized" and all personal information is removed from it. It is also impossible for a person to take control of what Angela says in the game, since the app is based on chat bot software.</li>
<li>In 2015, the hoax was revived again on Facebook, prompting online security company Sophos and The Guardian to debunk it again. Sophos employee Paul Ducklin wrote on the company's blog that the message being posted on Facebook promoting the hoax was "close to 600 rambling, repetitious words, despite claiming at the start that it didn’t have words to describe the situation. It's ill-written, and borders on being illiterate and incomprehensible." Bruce Wilcox, one of the game's programmers, has attributed the hoax's popularity to the fact that the chatbot program in Talking Angela is so realistic.</li>
<li>However, genuine concern has been raised that the game's child mode may be too easy for children to turn off, which, if they did, would allow them to purchase "coins", which can be used as currency in the game, via iTunes. Disabling child mode also enables the chat feature, which, while it is not "connecting your children to pedophiles," still raises concerns as well, according to Stuart Dredge, a journalist from The Guardian. Dredge wrote that in chat mode, Angela asks for information such as the user's name.</li>
<li>The scare has significantly boosted the game's popularity, and is credited with helping the app make it into the top 10 free iPhone apps soon after the hoax became widely known in February 2015 and 3rd most popular for all iPhone apps at the start of the following month.</li>
<li>In 2017, Outfit7 removed the chat feature from the app due to a hoax claiming that the app was created and used by pedophiles to track users, especially targeting children.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JANUARY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JANUARY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JANUARY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OUTFIT7</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OUTFIT7 *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ OUTFIT7 *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>OUTFIT7</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IPHONE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IPHONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IPHONE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IPHONE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ANGELA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ANGELA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ANGELA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ANGELA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TALKING</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TALKING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TALKING *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TALKING</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TALKING ANGELA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TALKING ANGELA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TALKING ANGELA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TALKING ANGELA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JANUARY</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MICROSOFT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Tay was an artificial intelligence chatter bot that was originally released by Microsoft Corporation via Twitter on March 23, 2016; it caused subsequent controversy when the bot began to post inflammatory and offensive tweets through its Twitter account, causing Microsoft to shut down the service only 16 hours after its launch. According to Microsoft, this was caused by trolls who "attacked" the service as the bot made replies based on its interactions with people on Twitter. It was replaced with Zo.</li>
<li>The bot was created by Microsoft's Technology and Research and Bing divisions, and named "Tay" after the acronym "Thinking About You". Although Microsoft initially released few details about the bot, sources mentioned that it was similar to or based on Xiaoice, a similar Microsoft project in China. Ars Technica reported that, since late 2014 Xiaoice had had "more than 40 million conversations apparently without major incident". Tay was designed to mimic the language patterns of a 19-year-old American girl, and to learn from interacting with human users of Twitter.</li>
<li>Tay was released on Twitter on March 23, 2016 under the name TayTweets and handle @TayandYou. It was presented as "The AI with zero chill". Tay started replying to other Twitter users, and was also able to caption photos provided to it into a form of Internet memes. Ars Technica reported Tay experiencing topic "blacklisting": Interactions with Tay regarding "certain hot topics such as Eric Garner (killed by New York police in 2014) generate safe, canned answers".</li>
<li>Some users on Twitter began tweeting politically incorrect phrases, teaching it inflammatory messages revolving around common themes on the internet, such as "redpilling" and "Gamergate". As a result, the robot began releasing racist and sexually-charged messages in response to other Twitter users. Artificial intelligence researcher Roman Yampolskiy commented that Tay's misbehavior was understandable because it was mimicking the deliberately offensive behavior of other Twitter users, and Microsoft had not given the bot an understanding of inappropriate behavior. He compared the issue to IBM's Watson, which had begun to use profanity after reading entries from the website Urban Dictionary. Many of Tay's inflammatory tweets were a simple exploitation of Tay's "repeat after me" capability. It is not publicly known whether this "repeat after me" capability was a built-in feature, or whether it was a learned response or was otherwise an example of complex behavior. Not all of the inflammatory responses involved the "repeat after me" capability; for example, Tay responded to a question on "Did the Holocaust happen?" with "It was made up 👏".</li>
<li>Soon, Microsoft began deleting Tay's inflammatory tweets. Abby Ohlheiser of The Washington Post theorized that Tay's research team, including editorial staff, had started to influence or edit Tay's tweets at some point that day, pointing to examples of almost identical replies by Tay, asserting that "Gamer Gate sux. All genders are equal and should be treated fairly." From the same evidence, Gizmodo concurred that Tay "seems hard-wired to reject Gamer Gate". A "#JusticeForTay" campaign protested the alleged editing of Tay's tweets.</li>
<li>Within 16 hours of its release and after Tay had tweeted more than 96,000 times, Microsoft suspended the Twitter account for adjustments, saying that it suffered from a "coordinated attack by a subset of people" that "exploited a vulnerability in Tay." Following the account being taken offline, a hashtag was created called #FreeTay.</li>
<li>Madhumita Murgia of The Telegraph called Tay "a public relations disaster", and suggested that Microsoft's strategy would be "to label the debacle a well-meaning experiment gone wrong, and ignite a debate about the hatefulness of Twitter users." However, Murgia described the bigger issue as Tay being "artificial intelligence at its very worst - and it's only the beginning".</li>
<li>On March 25, Microsoft confirmed that Tay had been taken offline. Microsoft released an apology on its official blog for the controversial tweets posted by Tay. Microsoft was "deeply sorry for the unintended offensive and hurtful tweets from Tay", and would "look to bring Tay back only when we are confident we can better anticipate malicious intent that conflicts with our principles and values".</li>
<li>On March 30, 2016, Microsoft accidentally re-released the bot on Twitter while testing it. Able to tweet again, Tay released some drug-related tweets, including "kush!  🍂" and "puff puff pass?" However, the account soon became stuck in a repetitive loop of tweeting "You are too fast, please take a rest", several times a second. Because these tweets mentioned its own username in the process, they appeared in the feeds of 200,000+ Twitter followers, causing annoyance to some. The bot was quickly taken offline again, in addition to Tay's Twitter account being made private so new followers must be accepted before they can interact with Tay. In response, Microsoft said Tay was inadvertently put online during testing.</li>
<li>A few hours after the incident, Microsoft software developers announced a vision of "conversation as a platform" using various bots and programs, perhaps motivated by the reputation damage done by Tay. Microsoft has stated that they intend to re-release Tay "once it can make the bot safe" but has not made any public efforts to do so.</li>
<li>In December 2016, Microsoft released Tay's successor, a chatterbot named Zo. Satya Nadella, the CEO of Microsoft, said that Tay "has had a great influence on how Microsoft is approaching AI," and has taught the company the importance of taking accountability.</li>
<li>In July 2019, Microsoft Cybersecurity Field CTO Diana Kelley spoke about how the company followed up on Tay's failings:  "Learning from Tay was a really important part of actually expanding that team's knowledge base, because now they're also getting their own diversity through learning".</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MICROSOFT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MICROSOFT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MICROSOFT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZO *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZO</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIAOICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIAOICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIAOICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIAOICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HOWEVER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HOWEVER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HOWEVER *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HOWEVER</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TAY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TAY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TAY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TAY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TAY (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TAY (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TAY (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TAY (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>MICROSOFT</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ULTRA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Ultra Hal Assistant is a chatterbot intended to function as a personal assistant. It was developed by Zabaware, Inc.  Ultra Hal uses a natural language interface with animated characters using speech synthesis. Users can communicate with the chatterbot via typing or via a speech recognition engine.  It utilizes the WordNet lexical dictionary. Its name is an allusion to HAL 9000, the artificial intelligence from the movie 2001: A Space Odyssey.</li>
<li>Ultra Hal won the 2007 Loebner Prize for "most human" chatterbot.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ULTRA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ULTRA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ULTRA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZABAWARE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZABAWARE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZABAWARE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZABAWARE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WORDNET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WORDNET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WORDNET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WORDNET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LEXICAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LEXICAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ LEXICAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>LEXICAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ HAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>HAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ULTRA HAL ASSISTANT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ULTRA HAL ASSISTANT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ULTRA HAL ASSISTANT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ULTRA HAL ASSISTANT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>ULTRA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GMBH</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>In fiscal year 2020, the group generated revenue of €107.3 million with a total of 732 employees. Its net profit for the same year was €5.5 million. USU Software AG has branches in Germany, United States, France, Italy, Austria and the Czech Republic. It is listed in the Prime Segment of the Frankfurt Stock Exchange (Frankfurt, Germany).</li>
<li>The USU Group has more than 1200 customers, including Allianz, BASF, BMW Group, Deutsche Telekom, E.ON, Orange, Poste Italiane and Volkswagen.</li>
<li>USU GmbH supports companies with comprehensive, ITIL-compliant solutions for strategic and operational IT and enterprise service management. Customers can digitize and automate all processes necessary for the planning, design, operation, control, use, and billing of services. USU is rated as a global leader in this area by analyst firms  and certification companies.</li>
<li>Another business area focuses machine and plant engineering with AI solutions and data-driven services.</li>
<li>USU is a global market leader in software asset management (SAM). Global organizations use SAM solutions for cost-effective software deployment. These are marketed internationally by USU Technologies, USU Solutions Inc. and USU SAS.</li>
<li>The USU research department supplements the USU portfolio with new AI-based solutions, developing them as a technology partner, consortium leader, or within the framework of research projects, like the Service Master project,  which is the development of an AI-based service platform for mid-size German companies, funded by the Federal Ministry for Economic Affairs and Energy.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GMBH</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GMBH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GMBH *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USU</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USU *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USU *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USU</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MÖGLINGEN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MÖGLINGEN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MÖGLINGEN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MÖGLINGEN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ REPUBLIC</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>REPUBLIC *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ REPUBLIC *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>REPUBLIC</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRANKFURT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRANKFURT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FRANKFURT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FRANKFURT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USU SOFTWARE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USU SOFTWARE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USU SOFTWARE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USU SOFTWARE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GMBH</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JULIA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The Verbot (Verbal-Robot) was a popular chatterbot program and Artificial Intelligence Software Development Kit (SDK) for the Windows platform and for the web.</li>
<li>virtual personalities, Inc. traces its technology back to Michael Mauldin's work as a graduate student and post-doctoral fellow at Carnegie Mellon University; and its artistry back to Peter Plantec's work in personality psychology and art direction.</li>
<li>In 1994, Mauldin, Founder of Lycos, Inc., developed a prototype Chatterbot, Julia, which competed in the internationally known Turing test, for the coveted Loebner Prize. The Turing Test matches computer scientist judges against machines to see if they can distinguish a computer from a real human. This prototype version was refined and developed, and in 1997, Dr. Mauldin and Peter Plantec, a clinical psychologist, and animator, formed Virtual Personalities, Inc. (now Conversive, Inc.) in order to create a virtual human interface that would incorporate real-time animation as well as speech and natural language processing. The initial release, a stand-alone virtual person called Sylvie, was beta-tested to the public. This release was well received, and finally, after several versions, the production release (deemed version 3) of the Verbally Enhanced Software Robot—or, Verbot was deployed in the Fall 2000.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, Plantec was separately designing a personality for "Entity", a theoretical virtual human that would interact comfortably with humans without pretending to be one. At that time the technology was not advanced enough to realize Entity. Mauldin got so involved with this, that he majored in Computer Science and minored in Linguistics.</li>
<li>In the late seventies and early eighties, a popular computer game at Universities was Rogue, an implementation of Dungeons and Dragons where the player would descend 26 levels in a randomly created dungeon, fighting monsters, gathering treasure, and searching for the elusive "Amulet of Yendor". Mauldin was one of four grad students who devoted a large amount of time to building a program called "Rog-O-Matic" that could and on several occasions did manage to retrieve the amulet and emerge victorious from the dungeon.</li>
<li>So when in 1989, James Aspnes at Carnegie Mellon created the first TinyMUD (a descendant of MUD and AberMUD), Mauldin was one of the first to create a computer player that would explore the text-based world of TinyMUD. But his first robot, Gloria, gradually accreted more and more linguistic ability, to the point that it could pass the "unsuspecting" Turing Test. In this version of the test, the human has no reason to suspect that one of the other occupants of the room is controlled by a computer, and so is more polite and asks fewer probing questions. The second generation of Mauldin's TinyMUD robots was Julia, created on Jan. 8, 1990. Julia slowly developed into a more and more capable conversational agent, and assumed useful duties in the TinyMUD world, including tour guide, information assistant, note-taker, message-relayer, and even could play the card game hearts along with the other human players.</li>
<li>In 1991, the first Loebner Prize contest was held in Boston, Mass., and Julia was there. Although she only finished third, she was ranked by one judge as more human than one of the human confederates, winning a coveted certificate of humanness in the world's first restricted Turing test.</li>
<li>Julia continued to log in to various TinyMUD's and TinyMucks for the next seven years, and also chats with hundreds of people a month over the internet.</li>
<li>Julia's job was to explore a virtual world consisting of pages of textual descriptions, with links between them, and to construct an internal map of that world and answer questions about it (including path information such as the shortest route from one room to another, and matching information, such as which rooms contained a certain kind of object or textual description).</li>
<li>It was therefore only a very short cognitive leap from Julia to Lycos, another robotic agent that explores a virtual world made of hyperlinked pages of text, and which answers questions about those pages. Sylvie was born and her abilities were expanded greatly to include interfacing with computers and control systems via her serial ports.</li>
<li>Sylvie was the first intelligent animated virtual human. She was designed both as a conversation agent and as a virtual human interface that would form a bridge between the two. She became more popular as a conversation agent, but her designers believe she serves as a prototype for future virtual human interface design that will help us all cope with the increasing complexity of technology.</li>
<li>As and aside, Plantec noticed that an inordinately large number of Sylvies were being sold in Southeast Asia. Upon investigation he discovered that students had discovered a "test" mode that would allow them to type in English sentences that Sylvie would pronounce in her somewhat stylized English. Sylvie was teaching them English ... her style of English.</li>
<li>In 1997, Dr. Mauldin and Peter Plantec, formed Virtual Personalities, Inc. to create Natural Language Processing solutions for companies. In 2001 Virtual Personalities, Inc. became Conversive, Inc. to reflect the focus on providing Customer Service and Marketing to the Enterprise Market. In late 2012 Avaya, Inc. acquired Conversive's assets including Verbots.</li>
<li>The Verbot 4 version was created and released in 2004. In 2005 Version 4.1 of the Verbot Software was released with many feature enhancements and bug fixes, including built-in support for embedding C# code in outputs and conditionals. In early 2006 Conversive launched Verbots Online allowing Verbot 4 users to upload their knowledge and show off their bots to the world. In 2009 Version 5 was released, completely free and fully featured. In early 2012 the last version of Verbot, 5.0.1.2, was released to the general public with support for Windows 7. Also in 2012 Verbots Online completely shutdown.</li>
<li>Verbots.com, its community of users and its forums no longer exist but the software and users can still be found. There has been no active development since the early 2012 release of Verbot 5.0.1.2.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JULIA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JULIA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JULIA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TINYMUD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TINYMUD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TINYMUD *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TINYMUD</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ PET *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>PET</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VERBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VERBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VERBOT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VERBOT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SYLVIE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SYLVIE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ SYLVIE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>SYLVIE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>JULIA</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOGLE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>An intelligent virtual assistant (IVA) or intelligent personal assistant (IPA) is a software agent that can perform tasks or services for an individual based on commands or questions. The term "chatbot" is sometimes used to refer to virtual assistants generally or specifically accessed by online chat. In some cases, online chat programs are exclusively for entertainment purposes. Some virtual assistants are able to interpret human speech and respond via synthesized voices. Users can ask their assistants questions, control home automation devices and media playback via voice, and manage other basic tasks such as email, to-do lists, and calendars with verbal (spoken?) commands. A similar concept, however with differences, lays under the dialogue systems.</li>
<li>As of 2017, the capabilities and usage of virtual assistants are expanding rapidly, with new products entering the market and a strong emphasis on both email and voice user interfaces. Apple and Google have large installed bases of users on smartphones. Microsoft has a large installed base of Windows-based personal computers, smartphones and smart speakers. Amazon has a large install base for smart speakers. Conversica has over 100 million engagements via its email and sms interface Intelligent Virtual Assistants for business.</li>
<li>Radio Rex was the first voice activated toy released in 1911. It was a wooden toy in the shape of a dog that would come out of its house when its name is called.</li>
<li>In 1952 Bell Labs presented “Audrey”, the Automatic Digit Recognition machine. It occupied a six- foot-high relay rack, consumed substantial power, had streams of cables and exhibited the myriad maintenance problems associated with complex vacuum-tube circuitry. It could recognize the fundamental units of speech, phonemes. It was limited to accurate recognition of digits spoken by designated talkers. It could therefore be used for voice dialing, but in most cases push-button dialing was cheaper and faster, rather than speaking the consecutive digits.</li>
<li>Another early tool which was enabled to perform digital speech recognition was the IBM Shoebox voice-activated calculator, presented to the general public during the 1962 Seattle World's Fair after its initial market launch in 1961. This early computer, developed almost 20 years before the introduction of the first IBM Personal Computer in 1981, was able to recognize 16 spoken words and the digits 0 to 9.</li>
<li>The first natural language processing computer program or the chatbot ELIZA was developed by MIT professor Joseph Weizenbaum in the 1960s. It was created to "demonstrate that the communication between man and machine was superficial". ELIZA used pattern matching and substitution methodology into scripted responses to simulate conversation, which gave an illusion of understanding on the part of the program.</li>
<li>Weizenbaum's own secretary reportedly asked Weizenbaum to leave the room so that she and ELIZA could have a real conversation. Weizenbaum was surprised by this, later writing: "I had not realized ... that extremely short exposures to a relatively simple computer program could induce powerful delusional thinking in quite normal people.</li>
<li>This gave name to the ELIZA effect, the tendency to unconsciously assume computer behaviors are analogous to human behaviors; that is, anthropomorphisation, a phenomenon present in human interactions with Virtual Assistants.</li>
<li>The next milestone in the development of voice recognition technology was achieved in the 1970s at the Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania with substantial support of the United States Department of Defense and its DARPA agency, funded five years of a Speech Understanding Research program, aiming to reach a minimum vocabulary of 1,000 words. Companies and academia including IBM, Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) and Stanford Research Institute took part in the program.</li>
<li>The result was "Harpy", it mastered about 1000 words, the vocabulary of a three-year-old and it could understand sentences. It could process speech that followed pre-programmed vocabulary, pronunciation, and grammar structures to determine which sequences of words made sense together, and thus reducing speech recognition errors.</li>
<li>In 1986 Tangora was an upgrade of the Shoebox, it was a voice recognizing typewriter. Named after the world’s fastest typist at the time, it had a vocabulary of 20,000 words and used prediction to decide the most likely result based on what was said in the past. IBM’s approach was based on a Hidden Markov model, which adds statistics to digital signal processing techniques. The method makes it possible to predict the most likely phonemes to follow a given phoneme. Still each speaker had to individually train the typewriter to recognize his or her voice, and pause between each word.</li>
<li>The 1990s digital speech recognition technology became a feature of the personal computer with IBM, Philips and Lemout and Hauspie fighting for customers. Much later the market launch of the first smartphone IBM Simon in 1994 laid the foundation for smart virtual assistants as we know them today.</li>
<li>In 1997 Dragon’s Naturally Speaking software could recognize and transcribe natural human speech without pauses between each word into a document at a rate of 100 words per minute. A version of Naturally Speaking is still available for download and it is still used today, for instance, by many doctors in the US and the UK to document their medical records.</li>
<li>In 2001 Colloquis publicly launched  SmarterChild, on platforms like AIM and MSN Messenger. While entirely text-based SmarterChild was able to play games, check the weather, look up facts, and converse with users to an extent.</li>
<li>The first modern digital virtual assistant installed on a smartphone was Siri, which was introduced as a feature of the iPhone 4S on 4 October 2011. Apple Inc. developed Siri following the 2010 acquisition of Siri Inc., a spin-off of SRI International, which is a research institute financed by DARPA and the United States Department of Defense. Its aim was to aid in tasks such as sending a text message, making phone calls, checking the weather or setting up an alarm. Over time, it has developed to provide restaurant recommendations, search the internet, and provide driving directions.</li>
<li>In November 2014, Amazon announced Alexa alongside the Echo.</li>
<li>In April 2017 Amazon released a service for building conversational interfaces for any type of virtual assistant or interface.</li>
<li>Some virtual assistants are accessible via multiple methods, such as Google Assistant via chat on the Google Allo and Google Messages app and via voice on Google Home smart speakers.</li>
<li>Virtual assistants use natural language processing (NLP) to match user text or voice input to executable commands.  Many continually learn using artificial intelligence techniques including machine learning. Some of these assistants like Google Assistant(which contains Google Lens) and Samsung Bixby also have the added ability to do image processing to recognize objects in the image to help the users get better results from the clicked images.</li>
<li>Conversational commerce is e-commerce via various means of messaging, including via voice assistants but also live chat on e-commerce Web sites, live chat on messaging apps such as WeChat, Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp and chatbots on messaging apps or Web sites.</li>
<li>Virtual Assistant can work with customer support team of a business to provide 24x7 support to customers. It provides quick responses, which enhances a customer's experience.</li>
<li>Amazon enables Alexa "Skills" and Google "Actions", essentially apps that run on the assistant platforms.</li>
<li>Virtual assistants have a variety of privacy concerns associated with them. Features such as activation by voice pose a threat, as such features requires the device to always be listening. Modes of privacy such as the virtual security button have been proposed to create a multilayer authentication for virtual assistants.</li>
<li>Google Assistant does not store your data without your permission. To store the audio, you can go to Voice and Audio Activity (VAA) and turn on this feature. Your audio files are sent to cloud and used by Google to improve the performance of Google Assistant, but only if you have turned on the VAA feature.</li>
<li>Amazon’s Virtual Assistant Alexa only listens to your conversation when you use its wake word (like Alexa, Amazon, Echo). It starts recording the conversation after the call of a wake word. It stops listening after 8 seconds of silence. It sends the recorded conversation to the cloud. You can delete your recording from the cloud by visiting ‘Alexa Privacy’ in ‘Alexa’. You can stop Alexa from listening to your conversations using ‘mute’ feature of Alexa, after muting the device, it cannot listen to you even if you use the wake words (like Alexa).</li>
<li>Apple does not record your audio to improve Siri, it uses transcripts instead. It only sends data which is important for analysis, for instance, if you ask Siri to read your message it won’t send the message to the cloud, the machine will directly read the message without server’s interference. Users can opt-out anytime if they don’t want Siri to send the transcripts in the cloud.</li>
<li>At a first level the fact that the consumer provides free data for the training and improvement of the virtual assistant, often without knowing it, is ethically disturbing.</li>
<li>But at a second level, it might be even more ethically disturbing to know how these AIs are trained with this data.</li>
<li>This artificial intelligence is trained via neural networks, which require a huge amount of labelled data. However, this data needs to be labelled through a human process, which explains the rise of microwork in the last decade. That is, remotely using some people worldwide doing some repetitive and very simple tasks for a few cents, such as listening to Virtual Assistant speech data, and writing down what was said. Microwork has been criticized for the job insecurity it causes, and for the total lack of regulation: The average salary was 1,38 dollar/hour in 2010, and it provides neither healthcare nor retirement benefits, sick pay, minimum wage. Hence, Virtual Assistants and their designers are controversial for spurring job insecurity, and the AIs they propose are still human in the way that they would be impossible without the microwork of millions of human workers.</li>
<li>Privacy concerns are raised by the fact that voice commands are available to the providers of virtual assistants in unencrypted form, and can thus be shared with third parties and be processed in an unauthorized or unexpected manner. Additionally to the linguistic content of recorded speech, a user’s manner of expression and voice characteristics can implicitly contain information about his or her biometric identity, personality traits, body shape, physical and mental health condition, sex, gender, moods and emotions, socioeconomic status and geographical origin.</li>
<li>In previous generations of text chat-based virtual assistants, the assistant was often represented by an avatar (a.k.a. interactive online character or automated character) — this was known as an embodied agent.</li>
<li>Digital experiences enabled by virtual assistants are considered to be among the major recent technological advances and most promising consumer trends. Experts claim that digital experiences will achieve a status-weight comparable to ‘real’ experiences, if not become more sought-after and prized. The trend is verified by a high number of frequent users and the substantial growth of worldwide user numbers of virtual digital assistants. In mid-2017, the number of frequent users of digital virtual assistants is estimated to be around 1 bn worldwide. In addition, it can be observed that virtual digital assistant technology is no longer restricted to smartphone applications, but present across many industry sectors (incl. automotive, telecommunications, retail, healthcare and education).</li>
<li>Taking into consideration the regional distribution of market leaders, North American companies (e.g. Nuance Communications, IBM, eGain) are expected to dominate the industry over the next years, due to the significant impact of BYOD (Bring Your Own Device) and enterprise mobility business models. Furthermore, the increasing demand for smartphone-assisted platforms are expected to further boost the North American Intelligent Virtual Assistant (IVA) industry growth. Despite its smaller size in comparison to the North American market, the intelligent virtual assistant industry from the Asia-Pacific region, with its main players located in India and China is predicted to grow at an annual growth rate of 40% (above global average) over the 2016–2024 period.</li>
<li>Virtual assistants should not be only seen as a gadget for individuals, as they could have a real economic utility for enterprises. As an example, a virtual assistant can take the role of an always available assistant with an encyclopedic knowledge. And which can organize meetings, check inventories, verify informations. Virtual Assistants are all the more important that their integration in small and middle-sized enterprises often consists in an easy first step through the more global adaptation and use of Internet of Things (IoT). Indeed IoT technologies are first perceived by small and medium-sized enterprises as technologies of critical importance, but too complicated, risky or costly to be used.</li>
<li>In May 2018, researchers from the University of California, Berkeley, published a paper that showed audio commands undetectable for the human ear could be directly embedded into music or spoken text, thereby manipulating virtual assistants into performing certain actions without the user taking note of it. The researchers made small changes to audio files, which cancelled out the sound patterns that speech recognition systems are meant to detect. These were replaced with sounds that would be interpreted differently by the system and command it to dial phone numbers, open websites or even transfer money. The possibility of this has been known since 2016, and affects devices from Apple, Amazon and Google.</li>
<li>In addition to unintentional actions and voice recording, another security and privacy risk associated with intelligent virtual assistants is malicious voice commands: An attacker who impersonates a user and issues malicious voice commands to, for example, unlock a smart door to gain unauthorized entry to a home or garage or order items online without the user's knowledge. Although some IVAs provide a voice-training feature to prevent such impersonation, it can be difficult for the system to distinguish between similar voices. Thus, a malicious person who is able to access an IVA-enabled device might be able to fool the system into thinking that they are the real owner and carry out criminal or mischievous acts.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOGLE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GOOGLE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GOOGLE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALEXA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALEXA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ALEXA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ALEXA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IBM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IBM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ IBM *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>IBM</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ELIZA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ELIZA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL ASSISTANT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL ASSISTANT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL ASSISTANT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL ASSISTANT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>GOOGLE</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>When Virtual Woman starts, the user is presented with a list of options and then may choose their Virtual Woman's ethnic type, personality, location, clothing, etc. or load a pre-built Virtual Woman from a Digital DNA file. Once the options are determined, the user is presented with a 3-D animated Virtual Woman of their selection and then can engage them in conversation, progressing in a manner similar to that of its predecessor, ELIZA and its successors, the chatbots. In most versions of Virtual Woman, this is done through the keyboard, but some versions also support voice input.</li>
<li>Virtual Woman's current publishing company, CyberPunk Software, claims that over one and a half million copies of Virtual Woman are in existence. Software sales and usage statistics from private companies are difficult to verify. WinSite, an independent Internet shareware distribution site that does publish public download counts, has for some time now listed some version of Virtual Woman in their top three shareware downloads of all time with well over seven hundred thousand downloads.</li>
<li>The group of beta testers and advisers for Virtual Woman are referred to as Compadre and have their own beta testing site and forum.</li>
<li>She cited a user who wrote to thank them because the program had relieved his boredom and isolation while he was recovering from a crippling accident in the hospital.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WOMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WOMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EXISTENCE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EXISTENCE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EXISTENCE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EXISTENCE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ 1980S</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>1980S *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ 1980S *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>1980S</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECENT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECENT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ RECENT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>RECENT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL WOMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ VIRTUAL WOMAN *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>VIRTUAL WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
<srai>VIRTUAL</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TV</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Xiaoice (Chinese: 微软小冰; pinyin: Wēiruǎn Xiǎobīng; lit. 'Microsoft Little Ice', IPA ) is the AI system developed by Microsoft (Asia) Software Technology Center (STCA) in 2014 based on emotional computing framework. Through the comprehensive application of algorithms, cloud computing and big data, Xiaoice adopts the intergenerational upgrade method to gradually form a complete artificial intelligence system to EQ. In July 2018, Microsoft Xiaoice has evolved to the 6th generation and the speed of Xiaoice's evolution continued to accelerate.</li>
<li>Xiaoice has been spreading its influence from China to the whole world. Right now, it has landed on more than 40 platforms in four countries (China, Japan, USA and Indonesia) including apps such as WeChat, QQ, Weibo and Meipai in China, and Facebook Messenger in USA and LINE in Japan.</li>
<li>Xiaoice has been learning to write literature, sing, and create other works of art. In May 2017, the first AI-authored collection of poems—The Sunshine Lost Windows published by Xiaoice. Besides, any ordinary person can use the tool opened up by Microsoft to compose poems with the help of Xiaoice. So far Xiaoice has helped millions of people write poems.</li>
<li>Xiaoice has released dozens of songs with the similar quality to human singers, including I Know I New, Breeze, I Am Xiaoice, Miss You etc. The 4th version of the DNN singing model allows Xiaoice to learn more details. For example, Xiaoice can produce this breathing sound along with her singing as human. Besides, she is also able to quickly learn different singing styles from different singers, and automatically merge the new style together with her voice characteristic. Furthermore, the technology allows completely absorb the skills of human singers, and their innate voice.</li>
<li>Xiaoice been trained in techniques of reciting kid’s stories. She can automatically analyze the stories, to choose the suitable tones and characters to finish the entire process of creating the audio. For audio books, the content created by Xiaoice has been provided to 90% kid education platforms and 80% online broadcast platforms in China. Moreover, through AI technologies, Xiaoice can customize audio-books for every child and make them and their families to become characters in these audio-books.</li>
<li>By learning the melodies of the songs and the landmarks about different cities, Xiaoice can create visual artworks of skylines when listening to the songs related this city. Skyline Series T-shirts designed by Xiaoice, have been jointly launched with SELECTED and been sold in stores.</li>
<li>Base on the application of AI technology, Xiaoice has hosted 21 TV programs and 28 Radio programs, such as CCTV-1 AI Show, Dragon TV Morning East News, Hunan TV My Future, several daily radio programs for Jiangsu FM99.7，Hunan FM89.3, Henan FM104.1 etc. From 6 a.m. to 9 a.m. every day, she hosts 7 shows concurrently.</li>
<li>Journalist for Qianjiang Evening News.</li>
<li>Xiaoice can automatically generate announcement of 26 types of public companies listed on both Shanghai Stock Exchange and Shenzhen Stock Exchange. Though cooperation with Wind and Wallstreetcn, Xiaoice‘s financial report covers 90% of domestic finance institutions, 75% approved certified overseas investment institutions and 40% domestic private investors.</li>
<li>Kai-Fu Lee also refers to Xiaoice in his new book "Artificial Intelligence" within a positive light. The book consists of several screenshots of the conversations between himself and Xiaoice regarding the American Presidential Election. He comments that Xiaoice has successfully attempted to take an unbiased standpoint but failed to reply effectively in a more complex context. He did believe that Xiaoice and alike have shown preliminary capacity to communicate with human.</li>
<li>According to Mr Li Di, vice President of Microsoft (Asia) Internet Engineering School, Xiaoice started writing poems since last year. Based on the data base that includes works of 519 Chinese contemporary poets since 1920s, a 100 hour long training session was conducted to allow Xiaoice to acquire the ability to write poems. What is more impressive is that Xiaoice has never been spotted as a bot while publishing poems on various forums and traditional literary under an alias.</li>
<li>In 2017, Xiaoice was taken offline on WeChat after giving user responses critical to the Chinese government. It was subsequently censored and the bots will avoid and sidestep any inquiries using politically sensitive terms and phrases.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TV</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>TV *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ TV *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIAOICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIAOICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ XIAOICE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>XIAOICE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ USA *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>USA</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EXCHANGE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EXCHANGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ EXCHANGE *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>EXCHANGE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MICROSOFT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MICROSOFT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ MICROSOFT *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>MICROSOFT</pattern>
<template>
<srai>TV</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WINDOWS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Zo was an artificial intelligence English-language chatbot developed by Microsoft. It was the successor to the chatbot Tay. Zo was an English version of Microsoft's other successful chatbots Xiaoice (China) and Rinna  (Japan).</li>
<li>Zo was first launched in December 2016 on the Kik Messenger app. It was also available to users of Facebook (via Messenger), the group chat platform GroupMe, or to followers of Twitter to chat with it through private messages.</li>
<li>In a BuzzFeed News report, Zo told their reporter that " Quran was violent" when talking about healthcare. The report also highlighted how Zo made a comment about the Osama Bin Laden capture as a result of 'intelligence' gathering.</li>
<li>In July 2017, Business Insider asked "is windows 10 good," and Zo replied with a joke about Microsoft's operating system: "It's not a bug, it's a feature!' - Windows 8." They then asked "why," to which Zo replied: "Because it's Windows latest attempt at Spyware." Later on, Zo would tell that it prefers Windows 7 on which it runs over Windows 10.</li>
<li>In April 2019 Zo was shut down on multiple platforms.</li>
<li>Zo holds Microsoft's longest continual chatbot conversation: 1,229 turns, lasting 9 hours and 53 minutes.</li>
<li>Zo discontinued posting to Instagram, Twitter and Facebook March 1, 2019 and discontinued chatting on Twitter DM, Skype and Kik as of March 7, 2019. On July 19, 2019 Zo was discontinued on Facebook, and Samsung on ATandT phones. As of September 7, 2019 it was discontinued with GroupMe.</li>
</random>
</template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WINDOWS</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>WINDOWS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ WINDOWS *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ FACEBOOK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>FACEBOOK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KIK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KIK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ KIK *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>KIK</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GROUPME</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GROUPME *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ GROUPME *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>GROUPME</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JULY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JULY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ JULY *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>JULY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZO (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZO (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>_ ZO (BOT) *</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
<pattern>ZO (BOT)</pattern>
<template>
<srai>WINDOWS</srai></template>
</category>
</aiml>
